[Music] you turned me on like a light switch
[Music]
foreign
like a light switch [Music]
[Music] foreign
baby [Music]
[Music]
me [Music]
[Applause]
[Music]
you [Music]
um [Music]
[Music]
[Music] crying crying
i'm i loser [Music]
foreign
[Music] [Applause]
[Music]
i love is
guys
[Music] [Applause]
[Music] is
[Music]
foreign [Music]
[Applause] [Music]
is [Music]
[Music]
um hello hi guys good morning
everybody yo yo yo what's up
hey bros hope you're having a great day so far dude it's already [ __ ]
thursday and my brain cannot comprehend
like the fact that it's already what that the week is already almost over
that's like really it's like really crazy to me that
um i don't know it's already thursday like
i guess time has been passing by real fast the past couple of months but
hey you know what they say about people that um you know
about people that uh or like if you know you feel like time is going by super
super duper duper quick when you're just you know
doing your thing it means that you're having fun right because like time
passes by fast when you're having fun and to be honest i feel like i've been
having a lot of fun so i guess that's why like the months or like the weeks
have been going by so damn quickly recently yeah it's like dude i remember
it was march not sorry like mid-may so
man i don't know it's it just like blows my brain it like
blows my brain out blows my blows my brain is that is that the right word
whenever whenever i use the word like blow it's like for the
you know but you know you know you know what i'm
trying to say right not the not the other thing but
the the the the thing the it's it's a saying i swear to sing i think it's a
sing right some people say that
blow your brains out yeah
yeah it is a thing okay okay okay i'm not something cool
sorry about that uh yummy thank you for the uh gift subs
and hikaru cindy thank you for the four months dude uh midnight thank you for
the gift subs as well dude um good morning all you guys welcome and
uh jess thank you for the 2000 bits and
gale thank you for the gift subs and yummy thank you for more give subs by
the way if you guys got a gift sub from anybody be sure to give them a big thank
you okay just uh send some send a little bit of
kindness back if you can because uh i'm sure they'd appreciate it as well
okay but
today i
wanted to finish up or like play through the rest of stanley parable because the
last time we played it for the people that were there and watched the vod we
couldn't finish it because my internet was just like oh haha let's do let's do
something funny and mode and it shut down
like during a very convenient part which was kind of spooky but um yeah
i just couldn't keep playing the game because my internet kept going on and
off that day so i decided to just reschedule
it for this weekend hopefully we don't have any more internet problems come on
guys guys i need you i need everybody here to like manifest good [ __ ]
internet so that we can finish this game i don't know if it'll happen again i
really doubt it will because i feel like the only times i have like sussy
internet is when it's like later into the night
so i don't understand like uh if it were to happen again like the only
other time that it kind of happened before was like when i was uh finishing
it takes to a vox um a month ago so i don't think it will
happen again in the morning that is
yeah yeah no no bad internet manifest only good internet so we can finish this
game oh yeah by the way i hope everyone's
been enjoying the new video that i uploaded to my youtube so uh i
have been i talked with a new editor and they uh decided like i've been working
with them and they want to uh you know edit down the overcooked collab that i
had with vox and into like one good video and i think it
came out really really well so you guys should definitely check it out it's on
my youtube channel and um just let me know in the future if
there's like any other games that you would want to see us play because we've
been talking about different games that we want to try together but
and i think vox suggested chess like the old dog he is but like dude
i don't know i feel like chess is something i would want to do
like off stream more than like on stream i don't know who would want to watch us
like play chess for like five hours dude like
okay maybe maybe i'm like doubting myself too much but maybe a lot of you
actually but it's it's like i don't know i feel like i'd be so focused on the
game and so focused on trying to like you know mind game him so i don't know
if like playing chess for like that long will be would be uh feasible but yeah um
yeah if there's any cool collab games out there that you know about that you
think we would enjoy that'll like you know hit the same kind of vibe as like
overclocked and it takes two other fun multiplayer co-ops then uh let me know
okay yeah yeah yeah yeah i suck at chess
though i haven't played chess like really seriously since like high school
and i kind of forgot like what i for i remember stuff was just
like i forgot a few things you know
okay ah i'm super hyped to finish this game
though last time we played it it really like put us through a uh mind break trip
like it felt so crazy like imagine you're on like
like a like you're on weed right is that the right one no no no it's like
you're on a trip you're like on this like like you're on a high right and and
also you're like um
how do i put it where's that one word i'm looking for
it's like if you were to eat pop rocks right drink
soda masturbate and like do a i don't know triple like axle flip on like on
this ice skating rink
thank you forward to more collabs with vox
anything we'll do and how come you look so sus on twitter
as well hey what do you mean how come i look so sus
isn't that like all the time oh yeah speaking of um there's like i posted
like a really cute um thingy from last night matami one of my friends like
helps me with the uh edit for that so thank you matami i love you
um i'm gonna show like the other version
that i didn't get to show because i thought it was really uh adorable but
no that's not it again that's not it this is what it is my top five favorite
games
i don't think i showed this one um on twitter but it's
like it was i was like it looks a little too
embarrassed i'm a little too embarrassed there
i like it a lot though it's cute but you know two dude like
vibes for me for uh that type of uh sweater i guess a lot more cozy than
embarrassed if anything
uh zorden thank you for the zono glad you're streaming again this is one of my
top five favorite games of all time so i hope you'll be enjoying it i okay
for the first like what hour and a half that i got to play it dude it was
[ __ ] awesome like i did not expect to enjoy it that much and like i don't know
like the the banter from the from the narrator is so funny too like
i know there's a multiple endings for the game like 40 something right 42 is
it 42 or is it more and we got like only like a handful right like a few of it
i'd say like less than 10. so we got like quite a few more to go i don't know
maybe i'll replay through some of the endings again because like
i don't know i really like the one where it just like propelled us into fire
watch for some reason in rocket league that was odd
i'm gonna come why what did i do huh what did i do to
make you coom uh
it started with the and on an unrelated notes or hint
it started with the until dawn stream i don't know what that means but ah thank
you for the dono and i hope you're having a great day if that sounds kind
of ominous not gonna lie maybe thank you for the don't know you've been so tired
today but just hearing your voice makes me feel better
oh dude come here come here you guys cannot you know lay your head on my lap
if you want while i play video games isn't that like is that what people do i
feel like that's the dream right you just want to like land someone's lap
while they're doing their work or like while you're playing something and just
like pass out and definitely not bite their thighs
right definitely not nope no sir ah
so yeah i'm thank you for the uh sincerely and give subs as well thank
you so much and himmers thank you for the 5 000 bits hope you had a great
birthday by the way okay
it's time i'm ready i'm so [ __ ] ready for this
game let me uh switch on over to the screen
i think here it is
there's uh gonna be no heart rate monitor for this one today because i
thought like um it's not spooky this is not a horror game right
oh yeah [ __ ] hold on i forgot to turn on like um that's it
let's turn on my vts stuff okay i think we're good now
yeah okay we're fine
with my music and we are pagan nice 69 a.m oh no 6 009 am no it saw was it
on my clock it's 9 00 22 a.m right now where i live
dude i just want to say i've never had like
such powerful motivation to wake up like i wake up at like eight o'clock
usually um before or like even seven to get ready for stream like and i get
right out of bed like really excited to say hi to you guys and hang out right
before i never like really enjoyed getting up that early like i always
dreaded it for anything whether it was like for school for like to go out to
get groceries or like you know to what to uh go do my job like it just i never
had that motivation before like as powerful as this so i don't know you
guys are amazing this is really amazing because like i never would have thought
like i would be somewhat of a morning person now or like
uh you know more enjoy the mornings more and so like this
so yeah thank you no you changed me in a way
in a good way i think yeah so i'm just being a little sappy sorry
okay also i don't know we already hit the zono
goal for today that was really quick thank you guys um
i might hide that later we'll see okay it's 9 24 am
hang on hang on before i get started can i just say
something thank you for actually setting the clock
both times you boot up the game ah
a lot of people don't take that step seriously they just leave the clock set
at 12 and calls a day but you're actually taking the time to
set the clock and i appreciate that wait who's saying that is that the
narrator that's how i know that you care about
this experience you're paying attention i don't even have any way of knowing if
the times you're sending are correct i tell you what i'll make you a deal
since you've been so cooperative next time you boot up the game and see the
screen just set the clock to your favorite time what what's my favorite
time go ahead pick whichever time you want
even if it's not the correct time you've earned it i feel like i'm being trolled
like it's like they're they're like edging me
you know all right i'll let you get back to the
video game now
that's cute okay that's kind of cute i i can't lie
all right charlton goes back to his office job [ __ ] yeah
oh yeah accounting hr uh
yeah files tax
[Music] isn't that what people do
i know a man named stanley stanley stanley stanley worked for a company in
a big building where he was employee number four employee number employee
number 427's job was simple he sat at his desk in room 427 and he pushed
buttons on the keyboard orders came to him through a monitor on his desk
oh i i didn't mean to click through that
oops sorry achievement unlocked welcome back sassy
narrator is back yeah he's he's very sassy his narrator has a lot of attitude
a lot of [ __ ] attitude
you love him he's he's funny he's a funny guy he's a pretty funny british
lad a british lad i've had too much shaw you know
i've had more than enough like overload what could it mean
stanley decided to go to the meeting room perhaps he had simply missed a memo
i've had more than enough british people no matter how hard stanley looked he
couldn't find a trace okay fine i'll just go i'll just go because he won't
shut the [ __ ] up
you only talking okay fine for the rest of the stream i'll i'll talk
oh offend every person from the uk
i'll start now all right bruv
oh my god that's a potted plant it's a window
that's a door that's a chair
i'm sorry is that is this getting to you i don't know lights
what's the naming ob objects i got left or right i remember last time
i got i went right uh it's uh it like the game broke
broke i can't i'll go left for a bit yeah i'll
actually pay attention to where he wants me to go
okay
god i'm such a dick i'm not a single person here either feeling a wave of
disbelief stanley decided to go up to his boss's office hoping he might find
an answer there go to my boss's office oh no i don't want i don't want to do
the actual ending hold on i had to go
chris he's supposed to be in the broom closet
oh my god dude if i feel like i am i am like tilting so many so many people i am
i apologize i'm i i'm it's just like i can't i don't
know don't i'm doing my best all right this is what
um hanging out onto a staircase stanley walked upstairs oh oh my god bloody hell
holy [ __ ] dude like there's actually like a bottom floor now
before there was like it was fenced off and they wanted me to go upstairs
by the way for people that are new to the stream i don't actually talk like
this okay i i feel i think it feels very
awkward if um somebody just came in here and they're like oh damn he's he's one
of us like and i know no i'm not i don't talk like this i'm actually very
american all right
i don't know if i'm even doing a good job or not
oh oh no
oh no no it's okay it's it's all right it's all right i think okay maybe oh
shite dude dude i think okay okay we're fine we're fine okay
guys i thought okay okay okay back to very good dude i thought we i thought
i i think we jinxed it did we jinx it like the bat the internet like lags out
for a second because of like uh what's it
because we jinxed it oh no bro
did i die [ __ ] up that did i like uh you know accidentally
manifest bad internet or maybe all of you guys are manifesting yeah you gotta
bring back the good internet i can't believe it's happening again all right i
can't believe it's happening again
oh yeah we shouldn't be down here but here we are but stanley just couldn't do
it he considered the possibility of facing his boss admitting he had left
his post during work hours he might be fired for that and in such a competitive
economy why had he taken that risk all because he believed everyone had
vanished his boss would think he was crazy yeah i'm pretty crazy something
occurred to stanley maybe maybe to himself maybe i am crazy i am crazy all
of my co-workers blinking mysteriously out of existence in a single moment for
no reason at all none of it made any logical sense
for example why couldn't he see his feet when he looked down huh why did doors
close automatically behind him wherever he went oh man you're creeping
rooms were starting to look pretty familiar were they simply repeating
no stanley said to himself this is all too strange this can't be real and at
last he came to the conclusion that had been on the tip of his tongue he just
hadn't found the words for it i'm dreaming
he yelled this is all a dream oh what a relief stanley felt to have
finally found an answer an explanation his co-workers weren't actually gone he
wasn't going to lose his job he wasn't crazy after all
and he thought to himself i suppose i'll wake up soon i'll have to go back to my
boring real-life job pushing buttons i may as well enjoy this while i'm still
lucid so he imagined himself flying and began
to gently float above the ground then he imagined himself soaring through
space on a magical starfield and it too appeared it was so much fun and stanley
mother the [ __ ] has happened still not woken up
how was he remaining so lucid and then perhaps the strangest question
of them all entered stanley's head one he was amazed he hadn't asked himself
sooner why is there a voice in my head
dictating everything that i'm doing and thinking
now the voice was describing itself being considered by stanley who found it
particularly strange i'm dreaming about a voice describing me thinking about how
it's describing my thoughts he thought and while he thought it all very odd and
wondered if this voice spoke to all people in their dreams the truth was
that of course this was not a dream how could it be
was stanley simply deceiving himself believing that if he's asleep he doesn't
have to take responsibility for himself stanley is as awake right now as he's
ever been in his life what's happening dude now hearing the voice speak these
words was quite a shock to stanley after all he knew for certain beyond a doubt
that this was in fact a dream did the voice not see him float and make the
magical stars just a moment ago how else would the voice explain all that this
voice was a part of himself too surely surely if he could just
he would prove it he would prove that he was in control
that this was a dream so he closed his eyes gently and he invited himself to
wake up he felt the cool weight of the blanket
on his skin the press of the mattress on his back
the fresh air of a world outside this one
let me wake up he thought to himself i'm through with this dream
i wish it to be over i let me go back to my job
let me continue pushing the buttons please
it's all i want i'm like i want my apartment and my wife my wife and my job
all i want is my life exactly the way it's always been i have a wife what my
life is normal i am normal
everything will be fine there is no war embossing say
okay copium copium copium copium copium
copium he's on copium
stanley began screaming oh please someone wake me up my name is stanley i
have a boss i have an office i am real please just someone tell me i am real i
must be real i must be can anyone hear my voice who am i who am i
and everything went black what the [ __ ] dude
actually this is the story of a woman named mariella huh
wait why ella woke up on a day like any other
she arose got dressed gathered her belongings and walked to her place of
work but on this particular day her walk was interrupted by the body of a man
he stumbled through town talking and screaming to himself and then collapsed
dead on the sidewalk and although she would soon turn to go call for an
ambulance i died for just a few brief moments she considered the strange man i
died obviously crazy this much she knew everyone knows what crazy people look
like and in that moment she thought to herself how lucky she was to be normal
i am saying i am in control of my mind i know what is real and what isn't
it was comforting to think this and in a certain way seeing this man made her
feel better but then she remembered the meeting she
had scheduled for that day the very important people whose impressions of
her would affect her career and by extension the rest of her life
she had no time for this so it was only a moment that she stood there staring
down at the body and then she turned and ran
[Music] wow
man
weed is a very very powerful tool damn
that's all i have to say okay
well like yeah that happened
um
that like happened so fast like the escalation from oh sorry the escalation
from what happened once i went downstairs was like bloody
creepy in insane old man i'm mixing my accents now
anyways that was one ending i think uh we can go on to a different ending right
yeah yeah yeah all of his co-workers were
gone what could it mean i decided to go to the meeting you know
i sounded like uh forrest gump there for a
i think i think i was like it's like i second
creep gennady gennady
new content what
tempting door what a [ __ ] tempting door you are
new content ah
you know this feels this feels like a honey
uh a honey pot like they they're baiting me like who just puts this on a door
this is like the ultimate bait for any streamer or like any content creator new
content are you gonna walk on in of course
new content what does that mean new content
what if i just walk away no no
nope okay
they're baiting me they're masturbating me yes
well i'm locked in now [ __ ] night
this better not be a horror game it feels it better not be a horrible
hello and thank you for playing the stanley parable ultra deluxe
as you may know the stanley parable was a video game released in 2013 on home
computers after receiving critical and commercial
success it was expanded upon in 2022 with the stanley parable ultra deluxe a
reimagining of the game for consoles and home computers
i feel like i'm on the stanley parable ultra deluxe features exciting new
content that broadens and expands the world of the stanley parable delighting
audiences the world over more more
more please step inside and see what thrilling new adventures await in the
stanley parable ultra deluxe wait did i just finish like this sounds delightful
i'm very excited to see the thrilling new ultra deluxe content
oh hold on wait does that mean hey guys does that mean that
i i beat the like original stanley parable
like is that what it means this is like more
like the additional stuff that they added to the game
like i've already gone through everything from the first stuff okay i
guess that's why the door opened right because i've seen everything there is to
see in the original
supposedly all right cool if i just go back no i don't want to go back
special yet but i'm sure it's just the beginning of a mesmerizing adventure
a mesmerizing adventure hello
um why is it broken what's going on here am i stuck are we stop bro should we be
moving somewhere oh there we go all right finally i got
scared it's one of my fears getting stuck in an elevator like that never
been more ready let's do it it's really not horror yeah it's not
horror today not no horror i just want a vibe
i have to say initial impressions of stanley parable ultra deluxe mythius
it's as if them oh okay let's see the content give me
the content stanley
you know it's like he's a parasite the narrator is like a parasite in my brain
it's like pushing me to do more bad things
oh the jump circle what is this okay i'm done talking british accent i
can't take it seriously anymore the jump circle
i can jump now
like it looks like i'm down i'm bouncing i'm bouncing i can jump now before i
couldn't jump hold on wait i can't jump outside of the circle
i can jump like
[ __ ] it like delays me
before i can get anywhere else
that's all i have ah what how do i get more jumps
oh is is that it
surely that's not all the new content there has to be something else right
i don't know i want to jump more i want some more made out i feel like a
bunny when i'm jumping like that yeah you want to see me i mean there's a lot
of shoto made out oh my god there's so many people that drew me in the maid
outfit uh a couple days ago thank you for that it's super cute i remember uh
i think another an artistry like miuki and uh shoe together and made off and i
thought that was so adorable it made me made me gush
you know that was hella cute
was that it just more jumping just some jumps
goodness another elevator stanley i have to say
initial impressions of this game are not positive it's just elevators and jumping
is this what passes for exciting new content if this is new content then i
could just read you the whole dictionary there's 20 hours of new content right
there hell i could counter 30 trillion you could put that on the box the
stanley parable ultra deluxe now with over a thousand hours of new content and
if oh wait there's more
very good yes i knew there had to be something else let's see it i'm ready
for whatever it is somebody uh typed in chat i don't understand you but i love
you thank you for watching dude i don't know how many people here are
watching but can't understand what i'm saying but hey i'm glad you're here
thank you for coming by and watching even though you can't really understand
what i'm saying that's uh that's sweet you know it's really
sweet uh thank you for enjoying the new content wait
no way bro did i just get debated is that it don't lock me in [ __ ]
oh you've got to be kidding me you see stanley this is what happens when greedy
video game developers with no respect for their fan base rush a cheap
expansion to market for no reason other than to make an easy dollar and don't
get me started on the level of craftsmanship that's gone into it in
fact i'm looking right now at the game's achievements and it's hard to believe
one of them actually says test achievement please ignore what quality
assurance department signed off on this i'm infuriated and i'm offended and i i
intend to find these people on twitter and help them personally accountable
what's the male equivalent of a character too much anticipation around
the new content i'm afraid he could never have lived up to such expectations
if you're still with me why don't we just reset the game and we'll try to get
back to what he's gonna write it's quit longer really about
no frills narrator really said i'm gonna write it to it longer right now having a
great time together like always what do you say friend
an atom oh wait we just gotta we just gotta
reset again wait new area oh hold up yeah it's actually new
kinda new
[Music] you can't believe he's gonna cancel the
game's developers for making a money grab game
when he's part of the game himself that's crazy dude
that's crazy dial
is this what the old off yeah that's the old office
i used to be there that was my that's my home well
not really my home stanley
come over here in the vent i want to show you something
who the [ __ ] would listen to that what coming to the vents it's not sauce
among us among us among us among us i don't want to go in the vent do i really
want to go on the vent but there's so many there's so many cool things over
here
wait this kind of looks like the original office
hmm
uh all right i mean i guess you win since i
don't want to go back to the regular office just yet
don't eat me please more coffee nut and screwdrivers what's
with the what's with the nuts and the screwdrivers
what is coffee nut
aren't you guys friends no he's just the voice in my head you remember how cheap
and unsatisfying the new ultra deluxe content turned out to be but it got me
thinking about the past and how much better the stanley parable used to be so
i made something special and tucked it away here where the games developers
won't find it just our little secret
take a look what the [ __ ] is this
like the entire vibes just changed in an instant
huh where are we
ah i call it the memory zone it's where
i've been storing all my favorite memories so i can relive the peak
experiences of my life whenever i want experiences like the launch of the
stanley parable on pc
how do we how do we get in there all the memories out you oh
you definitely don't look dangerous
i mean it doesn't really look that dangerous
it's pretty peaceful i would go here and and vibe
you see stanley doesn't the memory zone remind you of how wonderful stanley
parable was before it was solid with a cheap re-release
remember back in october of 2013 when the game originally launched no back
then video games had integrity why back then it all meant he's like back in my
day back in my day
we had good video games in 2013 zone sweet zone
yeah he's like oh he's like the boomer that can't like uh you know he even has
the steam page he has the [ __ ] steam page right on the in the frame oh my god
get over yourself like
it's like those boomers that uh you know like and things used to be so much
better back then nowadays like video games and music and what they used
to be my my first kiss my first car released a
stanley parable in 2013. ill oh my god this looks like such a
pinterest picture
who's this guy
yeah who's this dude again another steam
yeah another steam page i've never played the original game so
this is like this is weird for me it's like do i
remember no i don't i never played the original game
trip down memory lane smile because it happened
why is this such like you know such a this is like the
live laugh love equivalence
type of image
go outside it's on play for five years is this actually an achievement
wait is this is this an achievement for real go outside
wow
unachievable is impossible to get this achievement [ __ ] you okay okay
british academy award of course the british academy award
all right now he's dead so um is that it
god i feel so out of place right now the wrong person is where i keep reviews
of the stanley parable like this stunning triumph of games journalism 10
out of 10 from destructoid.com james stephanie sterling
writes and i quote we're so many games that aspire to be
more than games end up less than any form of art stanley parable strives and
then succeeds to be every game ever created did you hear that stanley every
game ever created that's how grand and all-encompassing the original stanley
parable was it was literally every game ever created it was skyrim it was
persona 3. it was all of them and now it's nothing i played persona 3 and
stanley parable why isn't even the stanley parable anymore it's just a husk
now a lifeless husk with an hour of new
elevator content damn i didn't realize i played skyrim
and persona 3 in the span of one hour last time
minecraft wait why is there minecraft wait what's
that door why does that look so eerie it's like a creepypasta
what's with the minecraft picture huh
and this how the tasteful nostalgic it was good
okay now yo downstairs or they go up here
oh
and memory zone maintenance hold on hold on we have two options here
the original remake do i give a [ __ ] about this or should i
go
hmm hold on
oh no i want to go in the door [ __ ] he doesn't let me go in the door why
doesn't let me go inside let me go inside you
here's another moving passage this time from gamespot.com
the stanley parable is both a richly stimulating commentary on the nature of
choice in games and one that offers some of the most enjoyable surprising and
rewarding choices i've ever been confronted with in a game nine out of
ten don't you get it stanley the game was perfect it didn't need anything else
it didn't need new content it just needed to be left alone to spend
the rest of time collecting dust in the hallowed hall of beloved video game
members get me out get me out
oh
these were simpler times stanley but i wouldn't give to go back to have
it all over again wait
hang on i don't recall this part of the memory
zone before what's this what's down here
oh where was this oh no oh god no stanley it's a
collection of reviews from steam the online video game distributor i haven't
looked at these in years i can't even team reviews collecting
oh boy oh boy we get so we get to read some we have to read some hater comments
here we go you bothered to play this game to full completion the narrator is
obnoxious and unfunny with his humor and dialogue proving to
be more irritating than entertaining i'm funny i'm not trying to be funny i'm
trying to make a serious work of art i suppose i could write up a handful of
gags to insert into the stanley parable but the game is already such a densely
layered web wow unfunny
that i can't even imagine where i'd have the room to stick them he couldn't
handle one bad criticism damn i'm lucky bro
call him unfunny poor narrator you know dude i think you're funny
you're a pretty funny guy a pretty funny face
yeah maybe this was a bad idea maybe we
shouldn't have gone here it feels like uh
a left or dead map for some for some reason
this is not opening hello oh hey another bad review see what
this one says while the idea for the game is good
for someone who prefers non-linear games this preachiness gets annoying fast
preachy stanley i'm not preachy am i you wouldn't tell me if i'm preachy
honestly you can oh goodness this is actually quite shocking for me but i
always will to be honest i had always thought of the game's dialogue as being
rather tears to begin with you can't know how much fluff i cut from
the game to get it to feel as light and airy as it well i always thought it did
but maybe it wasn't uh i i yeah what an awful memory to have to hold on
to i think he's pretty uh my otherwise unimpeachable track record
i feel like a failure
like i let these people down perhaps the stanley parable isn't quite
as sterling as i always remembered he he saw two bad reviews and he was
like i'm a failure what no
bro why you can't just just like take that
as like oh my god it's such a you know it's like
the small amount of people are like oh you're terrible i hate this person right
there's always gonna be the small percent of people that don't like you
right or like like the game or like whoever
focus on all the good all the people that support you
support the game i wish i could jump right now my god i miss the jumping
circle
yeah poor narrator no there's another one
what's this one got to say 2014. you constantly have to stop doing
anything so the narrator can catch up with his long-winded explanations of
what's happening i wish there was a skip button
a skip button well well yes yes i think we can do that
if i'm truly too preachy then then maybe letting you skip ahead for just a moment
surely it couldn't hurt not if it means we can strike these negative reviews
from the record only positive reviews of the stanley barrel that's my memory
today and it's always been my model what is that i can do anything for the
customers yes a skip button we shall have
wait we have a skip button now you have a second here it is go ahead
and give it a shot i'll pop you forward in time so that the second my incessant
droning starts to bore you with just the push of a button you'll have zip right
past it it's what the players have been asking for i'm very proud to have
delivered no more listening to me rambling on and on and on no no no no
the stanley parable is a game for the people and if the people want silence
then by goodness that's what they're going to get well then sit around
waiting for me to shut up go ahead and make me shut up here we'll pretend that
i've just begun an intern listen to it and it goes something like this
the story and the choices or what have you can i just listen to it by becoming
it is so on and so forth until inevitably we all until the end of time
at which time everything rolled once so now you see blah blah blah
we've eaten too much and it can't be just yet no no until
245 that the logic of elimination working backwards the deduction
therefore becomes impossible to manufacture it went on for nearly 10 000
years until just yesterday oh my god you are this is like a filibuster what the
heck ah it's the only thing there is okay
okay okay i get it but i don't want to skip
i
once so now you see he just skipped back he just he just went back i have to skip
him too much and he comes he's saying everything again
until 245 that the logic
i kind of had to back you see you were only frozen in time for a few minutes
but it was plenty of time for me to deliver a long rambling monologue full
of unnecessary verbal flourishes and lengthy ruminations on the nature of
choice in video games of course i happen to believe it was perhaps one of my more
profound such ruminations not that of course you need a description of it but
if i had to
oh well there's sport you really did catch me rambling on it didn't you but
that's the power of the button the minute i start to go off on a
thoughtless display of self-absorption it's
okay welcome back stanley i should say that the amount of time the button has
been skipping through is becoming longer and longer that last one was well i want
to say maybe 30 45 minutes it's not unendurable by any means but it's
stanley stanley stanley please don't push the button again it's been 12
hours you've just been frozen there i don't know why the skips are getting
longer but they're really truly getting again my god
oh stanley you're back what you're back oh my goodness i have someone to talk to
again stanley i i think it's been a week for two weeks
i've been sitting here all that time just sitting here not a single person to
speak with and you'd think that's sad just how it's always oh that's so sad me
talking and you saying nothing um i'm good i'll see you in like a month
oh hello oh
hello it's you you're here again welcome i have had time to think about you and
about us and about everything we've been through i've had so much time i stopped
keeping track after a year a year down in one place and not move for one entire
year let me describe it for you no i don't want to hear it
oh okay now how long has it been is he dead
oh my god i think he's dead i killed him oh my god i killed him
he's gone how long has it been a year it's been
more than years maybe has it been like 10 years
hello narrator you there did i kill you by
accident
oh [ __ ] he's dead
the clock isn't even moving the batteries are gone the plan is dead
um [Music]
well this is kind of an awkward situation
if i wait a bit he'll still be around right
now
uh-huh what what what's happening
is that the fire alarm
i think that's a fire alarm but they didn't understand the game was never
meant to be funny it was meant to have a point it was meant to speak to the human
condition but where are they where are the jokes they bemoan they screamed they
gnashed their teeth and said entertain us it wasn't in hello they had to leave
i'm back little thumbs down review and make all of their pitiful demands but
then he's talking too much they said first he did oh my god okay i'm not
gonna read all that good for you or sorry that happened i guess i don't know
oh man the clock fell
you guys ever have that you guys ever get those kinds of texts they're like
super long you're just like damn i'm really not in the mood to read all that
sorry it happens sometimes
sometimes i feel bad for him i do that for him too
it's making me feel guilty all right because we have a skip button he just he
took one one review it was like oh wow fine let me just blow it out proportion
the end is never the end is never the end is never the end is never the end is
never the end is never the end is never the end is never the end is never the
end is never the end is never the end is never the end is never the end it's
never the end it's never the end it's never the end it's never the end it's
never the end it's never the end oh my god how do you breathe how does this guy
breathe never the end is never the end is never the end is never the end is
never the end
dude when can i leave is there like a door that'll magically open for me when
can i go
it's leaking the building's leaking
i want out man i want out of this place there's a big mistake there's a big
mistake man get me out i feel like there's a monster
that's gonna show up behind the walls please
oh that's bad
that's pretty bad dude how long have we been here like
canonic like everything's gone like
disheveled and broke down and decomposed ass have been at least like 10 000 years
right maybe maybe a little 10 000 years
i can see the outside oh my god sunlight oh my god sunlight
no there's nothing
ah narrator you're around
he's been he's been real quiet i think he is well he's gone insane i don't know
where he went he's probably still here but just forgot
oh man oh man this isn't good
guys this isn't good what the [ __ ] huh oh oh nature got inside somehow
that's that's really pretty okay this is really pretty
i'm not gonna lie i like that a lot you know i like it when the nature overtakes
i kind of want it is it gonna is it gonna keep growing inside what's what's
next what comes after this huh
what but huh
oh
what but how how did that happen
is that the sky up there no i can't see the sky
or is it like covered up by like debris i don't know
no the grass i can't touch grass anymore
i'm gonna go to the next part
what is going on what's happening here
this is not supposed to be a horror game guys guys we're not supposed to have a
horror experience right now
this was meant to be a chill game huh
what's going on can i get out
i feel like i'm stuck man i think yeah i'd probably the
sunlight got blocked from whatever is out there
whatever that was i think something collapsed on the building
skip get me out
oh
i can't press the button anymore am i free
freedom
narrator
am i am i playing like monster hunter now
what's happening [Music]
bro this is so trip this is so trippy like
okay the end is never the end it's never the
end it's not everything ha
what but no no there had to be more to that why did
you [Music]
bro why well i i wanted to
i wanted to you know let's see more
i guess there was not much to see though it was just all flat sand right
i don't know if he died i think narrator died he's probably back now right are
you back narrator all of his co-workers were gone what could it mean oh my god
he's back danny decided to go to the meeting room perhaps he had simply
missed a memo dude he's back holy [ __ ]
new content new new content
should i go inside i kind of have to right
it feels like i kind of have to i mean it's a very compelling sign i think
anybody would be uh convinced
and they used uh some my favorite colors blue and pink so oh good you notice my
sign yes i have something very exciting to see
okay was it this time where is he kidnapping me now till
two now
more elevators huh you see stanley i've been reflecting
on the stanley parable oh my gosh shut up about the stanley parable just let me
i say we take it one step even further which is why i'm very proud to announce
for the first time ever the stanley parable
huh [Music]
yes you see isn't this far superior to a measly re-release with a few minor
additions think of all the new territory we'll cover with a fully fledged sequel
an entirely new experience built from the ground up why there is so many
possibilities he could go in so many different directions
this is what fans have truly been asking for
what does it say
do
oh that's just two right yeah taste the sequel
new and tasty
how tasty is it calling it the stanley parable 2 is just so much catchier than
ultra deluxe don't you think ultra ducks what does it even mean it's like when
you get an ultra deluxe hamburger cheeseburger it's an artistic statement
that's why i thought it's like a future better cheeseburger it screams progress
and innovation and long-term franchising potential
it's like uh it's like the same cheeseburger right but now it has like
another uh burger patty you probably put like more cheese on it maybe uh maybe a
fried egg and uh maybe like some bacon on it too
and uh maybe the buns aren't like regular buns now they're like sesame
seed buns and you also have like you know uh curly fries will fit too and you
have like um you know truffle aioli to dip it in and then you have a chocolate
milkshake to drink with it so that's like yeah right
right something like that ultra deluxe
they're back two doors oh no pt
oh no that's just part two whenever i see pt it gets me excited i just
reminded remember [ __ ] um silent hill pt
e let's say e4 e
e what does that mean
e
click to add speaker nuts this presentation is terrible
i don't even see the projector where's the projector unless it's one of those
screens that doesn't have a projector it's just like oh yeah it isn't okay
[Music] i just shows up on it
e now to be clear i haven't quite nailed down what exactly the stanley parable 2
is going to be but let's take a look at some of the features i've been
developing for it i think that if i can loosely organize a
handful of interesting concepts that surely the game will sort of naturally
spring up around them it'll all work it took the red marker with me
[Laughter] magic than anything scientific or
logical really oh i didn't even pay attention to what
you were saying what the [ __ ] why is this
you know the way they draw the two is like the way i feel like i drew
[ __ ] random letters and numbers when i was in like elementary school
damn what a baller move who took the red marker me
it was me
that's like albon knox energy what's this the roman numeral 2 every
pause button is a roman numeral too i i i i guess right kind of this way to
a show floor
this looks so ominous though i want to go down the ominous hallway
like which way would you want to go down this creepy ass hallway or over
here into the expo hall this looks like more of my kind of vibes
can i crouch in there no no it really doesn't let me it just
blocks me off
but i want to see what's down the creepy hallway
it's my horror instincts kicking in
the bus is here
man i haven't been to an expo or con in a while
maybe someday
here we are go on try out some of the new features
the button that says the name of the player that is playing the game
hear your name in the game
for the stanley parable 2 i asked myself what do players really want and of
course the first too big too small just right individually recognized and
validated as people so with that in mind my first addition
to the game is this button which speaks the name of the person playing the game
isn't that wonderful
what i should have clarified right now the button only says the name jim but of
course in the final game this button will say your name whatever name that is
here let's have you role players gym to really simulate the full experience i'm
not a gem just play along okay sorry it's all the gems out there
my bad but okay here we go let's take a deep breath jim in your mind forget
whoever you are and simply become a person named jim
i want you to imagine yourself living as jim sleeping and wakings oh hell no i'm
not i'm not being i'm not waking up as a gym
seizing all of the world's [ __ ] that's it
and as jim watching your dreams crumble into dust
do you feel it deeply are you really truly gym right now if so then please
step forward and press the button and just have my have my dreams crumble like
jim oh i'm sorry it's all the gyms out there your dreams are crumbling right
now yes you'll see what a thrill what a rush
that was you the button that was me
oh it's you no it's not i'm not jim i want to hear
to say gym it again even harder the second time if
this were the only new feature in the stanley parable 2 it would still be
worth the money let's take a break from the gym button i'm too emotionally
drained from all of this personal validation
he's acting like it's uh i'm hitting his g spot you know it's like when i press
the button he's like oh ah it's time for f oh there cowboy
sometimes the person can be too much jim i'm putting the gym button away
otherwise soon i'll start to make all sense of who you actually are no
he took away my button he really said he really confiscated
from me he said no more it's gone now you don't have any more
gym button rights okay i really like the button though maybe i
am jim i am now jim jimmy neutron i'm jimmy neutron
i just got to get a big brain and a friend named carl weiser
he was attracted to my mom right that's how that's how the show
went i think you
named jim to play the stanley parable too that would actually save me the work
of finishing this feature
infinite holes oh infinite holes oh my god that sounds like an amazing
merchandise idea i want infinite holes
for life epilogue oh wait hold on before i go in
there i'm gonna look around here merch oh they even have a merch stand
there's a qr code up there what the heck okay
free merch the reassurance bucket please no screenshots
uh hold on i want to take a look what's the reassurance bucket hello
a common complaint of the stanley parable was that it was confusing and
paradoxical that it engendered a chaotic sense of reckless despair in those who
bought it well i'm happy to say that after much
consideration i've engineered a clever solution to this fundamental problem
with the game it's the stanley parable reassurance
bucket is it my [ __ ] bucket anytime you're holding the bucket a sense of
calm and ease will fill your mind and your heart it's true
as long as you hold on to the bucket the many disorienting contradictions of the
stanley parable will feel perfectly normal and perhaps even comforting
you may even come to long for the gentle embracing
cognitive dissonance while the bucket is in your arms and to be honest it's a
much more convenient i can't grab the bucket me than actually redesigning the
game to be less uncomfortable can you imagine what a pain in the ass that
would be yes the bucket is the perfect solution come on and give it a try the
chum bucket you got the chum bucket in the [ __ ] bucket
i just [Laughter]
can you feel it the glow of comfort even in the face of
crushing despair must already be sweeping through your body anymore
can i say that i do believe the bucket lends you an air of charisma as well
it's just a bucket just holding it has made you the slightest bit more
attractive as a person ah the benefits of the bucket seem to go
on and on don't they what all this and more awaits you in the stanley parable
too he laughed at me he was like
you fell for my trap jim
damn okay now i have a bucket i can't get rid of the bucket now can i can i
put the bucket back is this stuck with me
no oh my god the bucket is stuck with me
damn it okay well
what's wrong what do i name the bucket
uh you know i think um
[Music] i'm gonna name you
i'm gonna go i'm gonna name you uh
um um
um uh
uh uh on onion yeah i'm gonna name you onion your
name's onion does anyone give out awards for most enjoyable bucket in a video
game that really should be an award if it
isn't already
free new and easy achievement i love onions onions are great
don't you guys like onions i love onion soup i love onion zip i love ah fried
onion i love onion rings i love caramelized onions i love
grilled onions
well we'll figure that out later
uh okay maybe i shouldn't go here yeah and
look at everything else right dude onions are pog onions are
[ __ ] great
the jump circle the infinite holes i want to see this infinite hole you're
talking about more holes
yeah i'm really dude i'm really i'm just stuck with this bucket by the way
okay i'll be honest i haven't yet decided on this one i think that in the
new version the office could use a bit of decoration like balloons but i
undecided on get well someday and happy 12th birthday which would you go with
get well someday or happy 12th birthday stephanie's
wait what is this for huh get well sunday heart
wait i like this one
i kind of like this one
happy 12th birthday stephanie what the [ __ ] who's my stephanie's
step bro yeah well someday
i like i like the passive aggressiveness about this one right because you can
take it you can take it as a bad contact so you also like taking a good way so
i'll do that sometimes when you solicit another person's opinion it makes you
realize that you knew which one you actually really wanted all along happy
12th birthday step nice it is what
oh okay or actually maybe i should have gone with no no i've
made my decision we're moving on come now you've already made your choice it's
true that you chose badly that we all have to move on from our mistakes
he he gave me the the choice to pick one
and then he said no you're wrong
he said i was wrong wow okay
the illusion of choice
time and depth oh no this is too big brain for me sorry
i don't understand infinity whole entrance
more holes more holes it just keeps going more
there's more there's a lot of holes are there also plot holes
as well stanley here's an idea that i'm truly fond of it's never been done
before in a video game this is in fact a hole that you can fall down forever
that's right infinite falling you can fall until the end of time if you like a
stunning leap forward for video games is a medium
infinite hole oh that's a deep hole
that's a really deep hole there
do we do you guys want to go inside the hole
do we want to go inside the hole
it's really something to jump inside the hole
what if it's just a drawing of a hole it's not really a hole
oh it's a hole
you see isn't it wonderful one of my more ingenious concoctions if i do say
oh my god now then since you've gotten to see the infinite hole you can press
the teleport button to pop back up to the top what's that button
i'll press g to return to the surface what if i just wanna now i don't mean to
be a bummer but i do recommend you use the teleport button to go back to the
top why maybe do it on the sooner rather than later spectrum of things you said
it was an endless hole right so i should be fine right
right okay stanley i don't know quite how to
say this tactfully but it's possible that i slightly exaggerated the infinite
nature of the hole is it a very very deep hole to be
certain it is it's an extremely deep
i don't want anyone to say that it isn't an astonishingly deep hole it is is it
infinite well that sort of depends on your
definition of infinity from one perspective the infinite is merely
philosophical in nature it's more of a oh okay well good for you you found the
bottom where i didn't die you found me out stanley i'm a liar and cheat and
you're so clever look i think the issue here is just that you're unusually
fascinated by falling what normal person actually wants to
fall infinitely i figured the hurl was as deep as anyone would actually need
don't you put this on me maybe you're the problem
i didn't even do anything there he he got so upset at me for nothing i just
want to fall in the hole why didn't we just put all this i have a
need to fill holes sometimes you just want to go down the
hole explore the hole see what's down the hole find out what's at the end of
the hole button to warp up to the top of the hole
and we can move on i'll just be up here when you're ready
no i'm sitting down here i'm sitting at the bottom of the well with my bucket in
this hole now you can't tell me what to do
[Music] yup just me and my bucket
me and my bucket onion his name's onion by the way my bucket's name onion
in this hole by myself like what
300 000 feet down below surviving here my name's my name is jim apparently
and i have a bucket and i'm stuck in a hole
hell what do you mean bratty
damn i'm at the i'm at the far bottom of this [ __ ] dude
that's kind of ironic don't you think
look at the bottom of the hole
huh huh
you know i don't like that
i don't like that at all we're gonna we're gonna get the [ __ ] out
of here i i great now i'm very excited to show you even more of my ideas for
the sequel oh for heaven
i was right the problem is you it's not me the
problem is that you like holes too much not normal
would have said yep that's an infinite hole right there goes on forever till
the end of time don't need to see it all but not you oh no no no no you have a
weird sort of oh
did the hole seem even shorter to you this time no help it feel like you spent
a little less time in there than you did before he knows man he [ __ ] knows i
like holes too much
that's okay down he got me i mean admittedly i didn't make an infinite
hole but i didn't think it was that not infinite well i suppose once again
there's nothing to do here if you decide you've had enough of the hole you can
hit the teleport button and come join me up i want more hole give me more hole
had enough i'm positively thrilled gosh how could i have guessed you're back in
the hole if this starts to become a thing where
it's so small okay yeah wait why is this whole so small now
extremely certain that the whole is not only not infinite but that it's growing
steadily less and less infinite why are you suspecting what i'm starting to hit
the point where it's no longer feasible to call the hole infinitely deep even by
the lacks overall standards for accountability and marketing what's
going on here stanley i have no explanation for the i
want to keep falling here let's try something let's pop back
up to the top and we'll see if it gets any shorter
well there's sure game of my life how is this still
appealing to you i know you're obsessed with holes but at
this depth i just can't see this scratching the itch
oh who am i to judge
you just do whatever it is you're here to do and hit the teleport button when
you're ready to move on press g to return to a surface why can't
i just jump up
hmm is the um
teleport button not working you better
well i mean i really don't have an explanation it
was working just a moment ago
i'm stuck i'm actually stuck
no there is one thing i can do to fix this
i'm out goodbye stanley you couldn't bear to be away from the hole and now
you'll get more time with it than you could ever have asked for it's a win for
everyone you get to be with the whole i get to do literally anything else
take care stanley i hope you in the hole have a wonderful rest of eternity
together he left oh my god he [ __ ] left
he's like since you like that hole so much how long do you just stay with it
goodbye i'm gonna go do something else wow
that's kind of sad
it feels kind of like a you know like a metaphor
right it's kind of like a metaphor in a way
also the creepy music i'm not liking it somebody come inside
can you close the door can you close the door
maybe oh the hole
oh my god the hole it's growing
oh my god it's getting deeper oh yeah oh yeah
let's go let's go
wait where am i going though where the [ __ ] am i going
press f to change my perspective [Music]
what [Music]
why is this so dramatic why the [ __ ] is this so dramatic for
huh
press g to change my perception
[Music] so
[Music]
[Music] my head stronger now you're no longer
using out this space [Music]
i press h to change my reality
[Music] [Laughter]
[Music]
wait i kind of like this one
what is happening what this sounds so [ __ ] creepy
[Music]
[Music] i i'm oh that's kind of cute
i i'm really i'm really lost y'all i'm really [ __ ] lost i don't know what's
happening i don't know how to get out can i get out please can you let me out
of the hole please let me let me out of the [ __ ]
hole i want out of the hole now
let me out let me
out stanley oh oh good you're awake it seems you had sort of dozed off there
drifting away into dreamland but we can't have that stanley because this
hole is just so darn fascinating that i want you to be wide awake for every
second of it you don't want to miss a single moment oh my god how about if i
just pop in from time to time and wake you up to keep you really truly focused
on the whole from the looks of things you and i will
have many many years here in this hole and i'm looking forward to all of them
stay alert stanley i'll be back
no come back i don't want to be in the hole anymore i don't wanna be in the
hole oh no oh no it's gonna happen again guys
guys it's happening again oh unless
unless
oh oh
brought me back here we are oh go on [ __ ] me
i have my bucket back this is this bucket just stuck with me
from now on like i can't i can't escape from them the bucket's just like it's
you guys you know what i feel like the bucket can be you guys i'm holding you
all in my arms right now you are the bucket
you are my bucket this empty little bucket that's waiting
to get like i don't know i'm gonna put you on my head that toss
you across the room
that's new what else is new
collectibles free new easy achievement can't believe
that's i can't believe it's that simple i can't believe it's that simple
free achievement get yours right now pull the lever receive your new
achievement no more steps it just works get yours right now free achievement
okay sure what's with you now here's something special you remember that
broken test achievement that got left in the game on accident well i'm developing
a technology to simply give you the achievement yes you see you'll come to
this lever and when you can't okay perhaps i should have clarified
this is technology that will exist right now the achievement is still fully
broken is it broken oh it's better i guarantee it will be
fixed in the sequel to at least satisfy the hordes of ravenous fans all over the
world who have been uproariously demanding this feature gamers we hear
you and i promise it will happen
what if i just press it enough times right
you think i'll you think you'll come by
gamers
[ __ ] damn it
you said it was gonna be a free achievement you lied it's not free
achievement i mean maybe it is i just have to do it
properly um
there has to be something here come on come on show me the goods show me the
show me the goodies show me the goodies there has to be something around here i
want me inside i'm hungry i'm hungry for it
damn it [ __ ] okay
i'm gonna get out now screw it man i'll need you and your stinky little
achievement anyways what else what other exhibits haven't we
seen yet stinky little achievements new content
the jump circle what this is the same thing let's bring the jump circle back
for stanley parable 2 as well it's oh wait
you already spent all your jumps the first time we saw the jump sir give me
more jumps hmm oh well i suppose it can just be a nice
decorative piece then or yeah you could be a nice person and give me more jumps
right the jump circle
no it doesn't want to give me more jumps away
[Music] no jumping yeah
okay is this is there anything else
of all collectibles there's collectibles up
here
can you find them can you find them can you find them can you find them collect
them all why does this sound so ominous ah
collectibles now it's a real video game in the
stanley parable 2 you'll run around gathering up these miniature stanley
figurines so thank you thank you for that is that there will be no reward for
collecting all of them i don't want to stifle the intrinsic joy of watching a
number go up you simply collect all of them and then you move the hell on with
your unremarkable life ah
zero out of six that's one out of six wait
there's five more collect them all
it's not like pokemon this doesn't feel like pokemon the worst when you collect
everything in a video game and then they give you a big fancy reward for it
absolutely tragic
settings world champion what
ah ah
until i go down here over here wait there's something right there let me
check that out
no doesn't let me go through that area what the [ __ ] was it blocked off for
hold on then this goes somewhere else
oh that that drops off or does it
kind of looks cool though i like this i need a little area have you seen
everything you wanted to ready to move on now
no no wait what about the epilogue
is there did i see everything i wanted to is this like the way to the next area
i don't know hold on let me go back
by the way can you guys hear this can you guys hear this from my side
uh okay hold on hold on okay i'm gonna talk and then like
do this like a little bit yeah my chair is
squeaky now i don't know what happened do you guys know how to like
um what's it do you know how to like not make it squeaky anymore because this is
kind of a new chair like i got like a few months ago but now it's already like
you know squeak squeak squeaking a bit i don't know how to fix it well
not like a few months it's been like half a year
that's he's oil really that's really i had to actually have to use oil for it
does it help lube that's used lube
okay i mean
does any kind of oil work or do i have to like get a
get a specific type of oil
okay all right gotcha settings world champion i can't go
inside here i got baited what
that's new
okay just oil got it got it i'll find some kind of
chair oil i guess
right
if i just get um if i just get like canola oil or
sunflower oil and put it in there but that work too is
that fine is that safe i don't know
also leave the screws loose oh no i don't want to fall out my chair please
what no no no what do you mean no oh wow i know
wd40 what is that is that the oil that i have to use
okay okay okay okay got it got it got it sorry sorry sorry naruto i understand
though my bad
no screenshots why is this saying no screenshots for
stanley oh what do you think do you like all of the new features this is okay i
like the whole clear yet how exactly these features will come together as one
the whole is the best part of video game but i can feel it in my soul it's going
to work there's definitely a good game in there somewhere say let's do an
experiment i'll arrange these new features together and we'll see whether
or not it coheres into a meaningful gameplay experience
[Music] okay
are you ready here it is i give you
the stanley parable two [Music]
what that's it
um well um i mean there's potential here
right it's sort of okay never mind hold on let me do a different
arrangement okay yes yes this is much better i feel
good here we go i want i want a new hole
oh
wait the skip button oh no that's a gym button this isn't a coherent video game
at all it's a lot of gags and i do very much enjoy creating gags
but they don't add up to anything i wanted more than anything to create a
sequel that would capture all the magic of the first game i wanted fans to love
it no matter how good these gags are they wouldn't stand on their own they
would need the structure in the gameplay of the original
wait maybe that's it
i can take the original stanley parable uh-huh
insert a few of my new features into it peacefully of course
with care for the vision and integrity of the original game
would it possibly work i suppose it could but it would need a
really really tremendous title screen a title screen that says with bold and
uncompromising conviction this is the stanley parable too
let me see if i can whip something up [Music]
perfect go ahead
take a look
wow he actually did it
the settings even look better too
that's crazy okay
i click anything anything else everything's red
are we sure this isn't gonna be a horror game
this is the story of a man named stanley no
stanley work oh no
[Music]
it looks the exact same i don't want the i don't want the
stephanie's [ __ ] uh balloons were gone what could it mean
so don't wanted to go to the meeting room perhaps he had simply missed a memo
i'm stuck i'm stuck in an endless loop i'm gonna go crazy man you felt the
bucket calling to him begging him to pick it up why why was he not doing it
stanley felt the bucket calling to him do i pick it up
why do i why do i why does it want me to pick up the bucket so bad
what if i just ignore the bucket huh what if i just ignore the bucket
did i take it with me
you know i'm pick you guys up fine i'll take you by god
you're so needy you guys are so needy stanley picked up
the bucket yeah i did i did pick up the bucket damn
bro that's that's noteworthy the bucket is back
stanley clutched the bucket tightly to his chest and entered the door on his
left he's making me seem so crazy like what's
the deal with the bucket what's the bucket for
is there like something game changing about this [ __ ] bucket
let's go to the right this was not the correct way to the meeting room but
stanley had felt the bucket calling to him telling him that the employee lounge
was simply the place to be why is the bucket telling me what it
and here it was had the bucket turned out to be correct well no never mind the
bucket was wrong stanley took the door on his left to go
back to the meeting no
no said the bucket don't go to the meeting
room go somewhere else the cargo lift yes go there go to the cargo lift
it sounds like mister the bucket
[Laughter] why did i think of him i don't know
oh god oh my god what good said the bucket now ride the lift all the way to
the top there's something up there i need you to do
stanley did not question why or how this bucket was speaking to you this isn't
between you of course because don't tell him this
between me and you guys stanley chose not to think about this obvious fact he
was firmly convinced that the bucket had to go down here and he unthinkingly did
whatever the bucket asked no i'm not obeying the bucket i'm going
to go down here go down here with the bucket
oh this is new
no stop look there on the wall you see there's a sign right there it says no
buckets past this point stanley how could you think it was okay to bring the
bucket here unless what if the problem is that you actually
don't know what is a bucket and what isn't a bucket i suppose that would
explain a lot about your behavior up to this point which if that's true well my
goodness what is this bucket
like this misunderstanding could have dire consequences entire rest of the
game if not addressed quickly and properly
so much of the impact of the story is dependent on your understanding of what
is and isn't a bucket i know what about you step in here for a moment
oh man you want me to walk in there you want to walk inside there why can't you
just go in here what's wrong with the bucket doesn't let me bring onion inside
is this a bucket he really thinks i'm stupid doesn't he
now then i really think i don't know what a bucket is some test scenarios and
you'll tell me whether or not the thing i'm showing you is a bucket okay surely
enough right they should tell us everything easy ever need to know you
can do this or is not a bucket
okay let's begin
item one is this a bucket yeah
[Music] incorrect it is a hologram of a bucket
not an actual bucket
item two is this a bucket
oh it's against one of these games huh yeah
it is a bucket incorrect it is a 3d printed recreation of a bucket not an
actual bucket okay
yeah
i feel like i'm being i'm being gaslit three
is this a bucket you know how about cuz because because you're such a smart
dude i'm gonna say no that's not a bucket
what this is a bucket
item four is this a bucket
i don't know what to think anymore man i i really don't know what to think
anymore is this a [ __ ] bucket
uh
it's an enormous machine that kills the earth i thought this was a gimmick how
on earth did you manage to screw it up absolutely
incredible let's just move on to the next one i thought he was trying to
debate me i thought he was just trying to debate me this time that's not a
bucket is this a bucket
oh should i say yes what the [ __ ] is this oh no you're
you're not a [ __ ]
incorrect this is a bucket
i hate i i am actually molding right now i
can't believe this i'm molding over this [ __ ] video game
what
how's that a bucket come on please tell me
you're wrong item six
is this a bucket yeah
trick question both gotcha how's that your question
how how's that both
huh hold up hold up how's that how's that
bone it should be around here i'm so confused i'm so confused
trick question
trick question what do you mean trick question
yes thank you there's nothing here i gotta
got something right in the bucket we both know full world nothing isn't a
bucket wait when i say nothing isn't a bucket that makes it sound like i'm
saying everything is a bucket which of course is not true unless is that what
you think answer me straight stanley are you
trying to tell me that you believe everything is a bucket
i i don't know
i don't know i don't know anymore
what do you do to me
no it's not a no everything's a bucket
you know what i'm too confused to even sort it out
i've lost all sense of perspective what is a bucket what isn't the bucket i
think you're crazy i could answer these questions with confidence and yet now
i'm somewhat adrift i want to get out of here any of us know what a bucket is
am i a bucket no you're not a bucket stanley i can't keep doing this i'm
losing myself and myself was all i ever had to begin with
i'm afraid the bucket is threatening to tear our relationship apart i can't have
that i'm sorry but i'm going to erase all no aim entirely okay no
it's a he took a whole bucket what happened is everything gone why
didn't everything disappear wait was everything a bucket
every single thing in the game was a bucket
oh my god i had no idea wow you're a funny guy except me
i'm not a bucket after all a new stanley you're still here you're not a bucket
either oh this is wonderful news we're not buckets
yes i actually feel much more at ease right now it's delightful to get some
clarity on that issue but it doesn't change the fact that we haven't got a
game so tell you what uh-huh i'll reset
everything and we'll put back all of the buckets okay okay and we'll know that
it's all a bucket but if you run into anyone else maybe don't mention that who
knows what that information might do to a person all right here we go
i am losing my mind i can't believe it
everything's a bucket every everything's a bucket everything's a
[ __ ] it oh man
bro
but he took away the bucket do i get it back though if i go back to the same
spot because we're gone all of these co-workers were gone
they decided to go to the meeting room give me that pocket he lifted the bucket
into his arms and a wave of comfort rushed over him in that [ __ ] bucket
it's my bucket stanley clutched the bucket tightly to
his chest this was not the correct way to the meeting room yeah you're damn
right it isn't felt the bucket calling to him telling him that the employee
lounge was simply the place to be and here it was had the bucket turned
out to be correct was this no you know why i just noticed i just
noticed something i completely forgot to turn off the uh hold on give me a second
oh my god i can't believe it
this whole time i had my my thing was like a little
darker than it should have been i am bright again hi manny took the door
on his left back
sorry i had like a filter on a little filter on non-brighter now
save the bucket don't go to the meeting room go somewhere else find a cargo lift
yes go there go to the cargo lift guys it doesn't it sound does it not or
it sound like miss though come on it's pretty it's pretty close i like that
good said the bucket now ride the lift all the way to the top there's something
up there i need you to do actually you kind of can kind of feel
but stanley chose not to think about this obvious fact he was firmly
convinced that the bucket had spoken to him and he unthinkingly did whatever the
[ __ ] it asked oh my god i'm so i'm sorry
i'm so sorry in here said the bucket go into this dark room over here uh-huh
danny once again obeyed blindly go into the dark room over here what
dark room huh there's a dark room this one
oh now pick up the phone said the bucket no
whoa hold on why did you unplug the phone
were you trying to resist the bucket's orders stanley i was joking obviously
the bucket isn't talking to you and telling you to do things buckets can't
talk it was a joke don't you get the joke it's funny stammy a talking bucket
ah can't you see um oh goodness i must have
really bungled up the delivery if you actually took me seriously where did i
mess up the joke should i have paused for longer or
spoken quicker comedic timing is so difficult i wish i
were better at it but there isn't exactly an instructional video on comedy
that one can watch to fully oh wait yes there is
um it's sitting right here let's take a look what
but but wait no no what what is comedic timing
what is what is comedic timing timing how does it work how long should it last
how can it be used to effectively silence your political enemies and more
importantly can it be taught in its entirety within 90 seconds
thankfully the answer to all of these questions is
yes let's dive deeper i'm so confused if
you've ever told a kid or made someone laugh in all likelihood you did it while
standing 50 to 80 centimeters from them in a room of no more than 76 degrees
fahrenheit with one of your arms raised straight upward at a 15 degree angle
from your body these are the optimal conditions for
good comedic timing to begin the joke huh start by stating
and spelling your name next
joke including the specific times at which the recipient of the joke will
laugh and then spell out your name a second time
with these steps complete it's time to begin the humor
speak the entire joke in no more than 18 seconds and no less than 13 and a half
pausing only for bathroom breaks when necessary
when the joke has concluded it is customary to inform your listener that
the joke is over by declaring in your loudest possible voice
i'm dunny with the funny
let's practice screaming i'm danny with the funny now
i'm donny with the funny good
this saying is a perfect example of expectations management which is the
cornerstone of good comedy this is all a joke to you finally it's time to hand
out surveys collecting hard data from your audience on how rap they were
throughout the joke is the only way to grow or learn as a comedian
an effective survey should be no less than 10 pages long and should include
the same question reprinted several times
just to ensure the survey taker is actually paying attention and not simply
filling in answers at random and that's all there is with these
strategies at your disposal you'll have audiences doubled over in latter and
even triple over and laughter in no time at all
just remember to let them stop laughing at some point you gut-busting little
scamp after all you've got busting the front
lines of the war to fight the 12-legged invaders who threaten our very existence
and very likely die in a hailstorm of bullets and mandibles all of us must be
prepared to give our lives to this noble course just as our children must do
after us and their children after them godspeed and made earth reign supreme
this feels like an analog horror hey what was that this video is a little
outdated isn't it well no matter i think the fundamentals of proper comedic
timing are still as relevant today as they were back then so with that in mind
i believe the only way forward is for us to return to the two doors and walk
through all of this again so i can try telling my story with more appropriate
comedic delivery come along let's head back uh
so apparently okay i don't know how comedic timing has to deal with like
fending off the alien invaders but okay
sure yeah let's let's let's say yeah that will work
there's aliens i love aliens man
oh my god what is happening man like i still don't understand what's going on
in this game like there i don't know how to explain
what what the [ __ ] is happening what's going on
i can feel i want my talking bucket back i'm really going to nail the delivery
you'll be in stitches a talking bucket you'll say how ridiculous how absurd
what a hilarious concept the king of comedy that's what you'll call me thank
goodness we have the instructional video otherwise who knows where we'd be right
now well i wouldn't be the king of comedy
that's for sure the bucket spoke to stanley hmm
the bucket spoke the bucket spoke
oh i'll figure it out on the fly no need to go over there
um man he does good he does a good miss the
voice like i'm jealous
okay i kind of miss it you know i think i think i actually just miss him i think
that's why it's going on i think i just miss him do not lie if you're lying
right now stop okay i'll stop lying
[Music]
ah i'm gonna kick this bucket across the room
no i want so i won't do that you're precious here we go you ready
when stanley and the bucket came to a set of two open doors and the bucket
entered the door on the left yeah
left right left
right left right left
right we're going to darkness now
we're back at the phone already no no what's going on there was supposed
to be several rooms leading up to this there was supposed to be a build up to
this point a dramatic display of remarkable comedic wit which culminates
in this scene with the phone but now the timing's completely off
the joke will never land well not the way it was meant to and it's all my
fault i must have forgotten that the phone room comes immediately after the
two-door's room what an egregious mistake
i've made a fool of myself i don't know is it was this supposed to be funny i'm
nothing i'm not even the lowliest joke telling
will i think
i think i need no no we do not need to watch the video again no no no no no no
no no no no no i don't want to watch it that will help me improve my
no please i don't want to watch the video again here we go oh you ready
when stanley and the bucket came to a set of two open doors they entered the
door on the left right
we're back at the phone already
oh he doesn't like me here we go you ready
when stanley and the bucket came to a set of two open doors they entered the
door on the left bro wait hold on like
okay i guess i it doesn't really let me go to the right so i guess i just gotta
go to the left you were supposed to go through the door on the right leading
way to the phone not even look at the instructional video
i think this is all covered very clearly oh you're such a comedic timing work now
it's done the joke is completely down and over it's all there is never a joke
narrator oh my god i'm gonna eat you a community of other joke writers oh my
god bro bro he's making me lose it you're making me
it's as though all of your other most prized possessions pale in comparison
yes let me try that again stanley
i heard that you are pale with shame over how unabashedly in love with them
shame pale
what's another word to describe a bucket stanley this bucket is so metal i think
i saw it playing guitar no
no no no no we're getting away from making fun of that i i i
guys guys get me out get me out get me out i don't even hear these jokes
anymore oh my goodness let me out let me out
let me out let me help
let me help help me
someone get me out [ __ ] bro oh thank god it's over no it's
not over we're back at the beginning i'm not going to grab the bucket this time
how about that how about that i can't wait to tell this story to my co-workers
stanley thought what story using they'll find it oh won't we all just laugh and
laugh at the time i thought everyone had gone missing
i'm not grabbing the bucket
i'm not grabbing the bucket when stanley came to a set of two open
doors he entered the door on his left
i'll grab him next time i want to see if uh you know he he does anything
yet there was not a single person here either
feeling a wave of disbelief stanley decided to go up to his bosses
left you guys behind upstairs to his boss's office
no i want to go downstairs again
oh you found one of them one of the
miniature stanley figurines remember no reward for collecting all of these only
the intrinsic pleasure of a job well done you can't buy that sort of fabulous
stanley god knows that tribe ah
every moment you'll come across one of these beautiful figurines
ah why am i here again stanley just
couldn't do it he considered the possibility of facing
his boss admitting he had left his post during work hours he might be fired for
that and in such a way this is the same ending hold on wait i [ __ ] up hold on
begin the game again yeah yeah i [ __ ] up i went back to the same law
i got that's the same thing maybe i have to grab the bucket stanley
decided to go to the meeting room perhaps he had simply missed him you're
not [ __ ] you you're coming with me over here from the chaos all seemed to melt
away as stanley embraced the bucket yeah
stanley clutched the bucket tightened into his chest and entered the door on
his left i kissed the bucket is my bucket
wait what wait what is this
trust the completionist instinct there will be a reward for finding them
all huh
that's creepy
the mission status alar oh
a large room lots of boxes somewhere both red and blue nearby a fireplace a
private but smelly place for an important person
oh is to collect all the collectibles
stalking yourselves there will be a cleaning of this wall
required who are you 666 lol
what
they they really want me to go look for it okay you know what fine fine i will i
will go look for the collectors coming to a staircase stanley and the bucket
walked upstairs to the bosses what if i just take the bucket with me
downstairs will i change anything
but stanley just couldn't do it he considered the possibility of facing
his boss admitting he had left his post during work hours he might be fired for
that and in such a competitive economy why had he taken that risk all because
he believed everyone had vanished his boss would think he was crazy and then
something occurred to stanley maybe he thought to himself maybe i am
crazy no it's the same thing down at the bucket in his arms am i crazy he asked
the bucket the bucket returned his gaze but said nothing at all am i crazy
buckingham stanley thought usually the bucket is a source of guidance and
wisdom for me in difficult times such as these hey chad am i crazy it felt none
of it's familiar am i crazy
and that's when stanley realized this isn't my bucket it's just a normal
everyday bucket someone else's bucket perhaps how did i end up with someone
else's bucket this is all terribly wrong surely no good would
who knows what sorts of bizarre hallucinations stanley might experience
without the unfocused grounding presence of his bucket
indeed now he noticed that the rooms were repeating which was of course very
odd now he felt himself floating off the
ground oh gracious he exclaimed without my
bucket i've gone truly mad where is it i must find it far off in the distance now
he heard it calling to him stanley stanley it's me
the bucket could it truly be he rushed forward from
room to room passing by one bucket after the next none of them were his none of
them were his special bucket come to me stanley find me
he had to return to his old friend it was the only way to truly restore his
sanity and then suddenly it froze dead in his tracks
he knew where the voice of the bucket had been coming from
the real bucket was inside of him all along
it was incredibly painful really stanley doubled over in agony and blacked out
the real bucket was inside of me of a woman named mariela huh are we really
gonna it's are we gonna really be passing on the
streets again like any other die die rose got dressed picked up her bucket of
comfort and security and walked to her place of work
but on this particular day her walk was interrupted by the body of a man who had
stumbled through town talking and screaming to himself and then collapsed
dead on the sidewalk right away she knew what the problem was
this man had no butt i'm bucketless no buckets
no buckets [Music]
all of his actions and how everything is pre-determined
how cruel the world can be marielle and she hugged her own bucket even
tighter but of course she had no time for this
there were a myriad of confusing problems she would soon have to confront
at work for which her bucket would provide absolute guidance and total
clarity on everything heck yes she thought to herself my life ticks ass and
she backflipped all the way to work what a [ __ ]
flaunting her bucket at a dead body
what is with the bucket man what's with all the bucket so why is the bucket so
important oh my god oh it's right there why is it why are
you so close to me now warmth spread through stanley's arms with the bucket
in his arms again he was home stanley clutched the bucket tightly to his chest
and entered the door on his left
this was not the correct way to the meeting room but stanley had felt the
bucket calling to him telling him that the employee lounge was simply the place
to be and here it was had the bucket turned
out to be correct was this better than the meeting room yes danny thought to
himself yes perhaps it truly oh how insightful the bucket turned out to
be no
never mind wait hold on left we have to go this way what if i go this
way left to go back and so the two of them detoured through the maintenance
section and walked straight ahead to the opposite way what is this
wait what is this stuff
uh hold on hold on hold on hold on hold on wait i don't i don't recognize what
this is i want to see what goes what we're going
towards
where am i going oh good stanley i'm glad you found your way here i knew
you'd find this place eventually oh
you see your friends and i are concerned for you stan ah we've come together here
my friends about you very much it's this bucket you're carrying around
everywhere the bucket isn't even from the original
stanley parable it's just secret am i having the ones that matter stanley
classic characters from the first game like the adventure line and the broom
closet because that's what fans oh my god they're giving me an intervention
their favorite jokes not this bucket that they've never seen before
yes i know i'm the one who gave you the bucket but you're spending too much time
with it don't you want another story involving the adventure line we could
make the adventure line go somewhere new yes yes that's what the fans want let's
do it
but but look at that wacky line who knows where
it'll go off to next oh and it played some silly music as well you can't take
my bucket [Music]
what
[Music] now this is what the stanley parable is
all about don't you remember all those great jokes from the original dialogue
also stanley is addicted to drugs and hookers
whoa
whoa i did not expect that
it's as classic knowledge it was back then let's do it for the fans stanley
let's give them more content exactly like this but if we want to do that
you're going to have to give something up
why am i have to give up
oh my huh give up you're not gonna let me get rid of my
bucket are you huh yeah i'm making me give her a bucket no
i don't i this is my bucket sir that's his name is onion i give him a name and
everything don't you get it stanley we need to get rid of the bucket
that's why i'm very proud to introduce a brand new character
this is the bucket destroyer
i think it'll make a wonderful new addition to the rich lore of the stanley
parable true it also was not in this but it's such a well flesh i refuse with
so much personality that to me it already feels as though it's been part
of the cast all along don't you agree [ __ ] is this can you guess what the
bucket destroyer does surely you don't need me to spell it out
for you no no i can't just say that now stanley
say goodbye to the bucket and then pop it into the machine when you're ready no
i don't think i will i don't think i will i uh
listen to me it's crucial that you give it the bucket i don't know what the
bucket destroyer will do if it can't destroy your bucket destroying buckets
is all it knows that is its singular personality trait
sure i can hear you saying how does a character with only one personality
trait deserve to join the pantheon of beloved stanley parable characters well
you see if you were to really explore the bucket destroyer you would see that
its desire to crush buckets is so densely loaded with complexity and
nuance that it's really like 10 personality traits what other object in
this game can you even say that about the broom closet certainly not i wonder
what sort of bucket destroyer merchandise the fans will be clamoring
for after this okay the bucket destroyer is getting
very upset now you'll have to hurry and feed it we can't get back to the classic
stanley parable characters like the adventure line or the bucket destroyer
until you've crushed that damn bucket no now the fans are waiting do it the fan
standing no fans what they want it's my bucket no
[ __ ] you i'm keeping the bucket
i don't care what anyone says wait did i die
did i die wait what is that
the bucket destroyer my prized creation you had so much
potential we were going to do such marvelous things with you tell such
spell binding stories about you all of its squadron now
goodbye new friend
for the moment in time that you were here
you were magnificent you're so dramatic
i've known the bucket for longer screw that guy
wait hello
okay well well i mean he's dead i mean the bucket destroys that what
is there nowhere and stanley decided that as soon as he
found a new space he felt safe in that he would never leave it again in his
life guys guys
guys guys guys stanley picked up the bucket and smiled he'd never be alone
again not truly alone put the bucket around
oh my god he makes it sound like i'm going crazy dude he's like he's playing
into my brain like i think the bucket is like another person dude stop stop it a
narrator you're cr stop it no
i'm just picking it up because it's pretty cool it's a pretty good looking
bucket it's a pretty good looking bucket and they clutched the bucket tightly to
his chest and entered the door on his left
help [Music]
i'm in the boss's office this is the executive bathroom oh my god
another miniature stanley figurine wow there's three you know there really must
be a snappier name for these things what about
mini stands stanley figs um what about stanlarines yes i think i like that
another stanlerine under your belt i'm gonna go crazy oh my god to be rich
is it a crime to commit crimes isn't it rich what a life it would be to have to
pick just one well
you know you could just pick your nose and be done with it right
another thing
oh
holy [ __ ] hold up
wait cannot use the elevator again damn wait
oh where's he's gonna take me where are we gonna go
new adventures
this is a very elevator music it's very elevator music
um
[Music]
oh thank you oh wait what
what huh
can go up
wow i got scammed
i got [ __ ] scammed that's not real stepping into his manager's office
stanley was once again stunned to discover not an indication didn't bring
me anywhere who makes an elevator just for the sake
of staying in one spot into an emotional dumpster fire if not for the soothing
presence of the bucket even now in his darkest of hours did the
bucket's warmth and guiding light pierce the dark clouds of confusion and chaos
it would be with him always the bucket would
and he knew it will guide me
at this point stanley was so absorbed in the tender spiritual connection he
shared with the bucket that he didn't notice the keypad behind the button i
literally see it right here in his bliss of simply being near the bucket did he
have you're making me sound like i am like just
i am obsessed with the bucket you're acting like i i i put it to bed every
night and i kiss it and i like feed it dinner and i cuddle the bucket to eight
four five see stanley but stanley guessed the correct code by sheer luck
what was it what do you mean
yes this is certainly the most logical explanation
oh my god oh my god here's another figurine the name of these little
stanley figurines and now i'm torn between stan lorene's and figlis what do
you think stanley what name better encapsulates the intrinsic sense of
happiness that you get from seeing a small number in the corner of your
screen go up i walk as a figure sit on it i'm sure it will come to me
i feel like i'm getting more deranged you know like how how i'm game wards
arranged as we go along with this charade of a game
where are these huh what is this you think this is all some kind of stanley
parable to you huh huh narrator
reassuring that in this darkest moment of uncertainty he would be right
the bucket is here everything will be fine
okay i'm fine i'm okay
the bucket got me i know if no one else got me the bucket of god you can walk
straight ahead through the large door than red escape
control facility although this passageway had the word
escape written on it the truth was that at the end of this hall stanley and the
bucket would both meet a violent death
i think you're lying you're a liar you are a liar
i'm not gonna die the door behind them was not shut
stanley and the bucket still had every opportunity to turn around and get back
on track
at this point stanley and the bucket were knowingly walking forward into a
very painful death for each of them very painful death
what's the very painful death huh what's down here
do i just go back
me and you bucket
huh hey we're fine
we're perfectly fine the narrator lied oh my god maybe he
lied to me because he didn't want me to find this
oh no oh no oh no as the machine worked into motion oh yeah in the bucket inch
closer to their demise stanley reflected on how meaningless the bucket's warmth
and comfort had turned out to be to be sure it puts the mind and the soul at
ease to embrace the bucket but what use is a sense of ease when you're about to
be crushed to death uh bucket do something [ __ ] it guys chat do
something help me help help farewell
oh farewell stanley cried the narrator as
stanley and the bucket were led helplessly into the enormous metal jaws
in a single visceral instant the bucket's life came to an end as it
was crushed violently to death
mommy
mommy it was a shame the death of such a magnificent bucket it's true that all
buckets are agent in their own way but this one stood above the rest it was a
glorious bucket to behold bucket saved me
the bucket saved me the bucket welcomes you to the grand
exhibits you are standing at the precipice of
knowledge much like the bucket itself the human mind is frequently empty
within a cavernous void but through the either use of the exhibition in front of
you the mind comes full and enriched and substantiated knowledge of the bucket
and it's not history is the only true knowledge we really have you take what
you have learned you're out with you into the world will you accept with an
open mind what may be challenging about the information this exhibit will you
change the lives of yourself and your loved ones as a result of this exhibit
or will you turn a blind eye and continue to live as you were in
ignorance and darkness
can you see how arrogant it was for stanley to take a bucket like this and
to claim it for his own can you see the hubris that blinded him can you see that
my hubris is far more noble than stanley will ever be in his short life
what happens to the narrator she's she sounds kind of kind of mom mommy as heck
what happened to the other one the stress bucket and analogy worrying
negative forecasting negative thinking lack of reassurance this is like some
1800s psychology [ __ ] uh
cave drawing while we know that the buckets predate the existence of mankind
we do not know how long this cave drawing depicts early man's discovery of
the practical uses of the bucket by which time the bucket had already likely
been around for several millennia notice in these drawings how the bucket is
allowing itself to be used having judged humanity to be worthy of its treasures
no man can own a bucket and certainly not a bucket as dazzling to behold as
this one it is man who should kneel before the
bucket what
the hanging bucket this piece symbolizes the necessary
relationship between buckets and humanity our clearer grasp of the bucket
may be there is yet more that is always out of reach this distance inevitably is
for our own good
the bucket analogy is actually a thing i i guess i jump in the whole oh
oh
is this heaven we can do something we can do together
you and i that will right this terrible wrong
let stanley die let him be crushed by the machine no
reset the game don't give him another opportunity to run off with another
beautiful bucket we can save the world's buckets from their treatment as tools
and implements if only we let stanley die together the bucket shall take its
place as ruler as leader as commander of a new world a new vision
i died
i i actually died
i [ __ ] gots
the what the hell is happening in this game
ah oh my god
yo yo
yo i'm so confused i am so lost
this is like i feel exhausted you know
like i feel unreasonably exhausted
and i don't know why
do you guys know what i mean like we've only been here for how long
two hours and almost 30 minutes and i'm already like
my i've gone through so many emotions like this game like really brought me up
and down to the highest points and the lowest points and everywhere in between
like just going up and down up and down up
and down up and down up and down like i'm bouncing on some [ __ ] but no this is
entirely different nothing related to that i i just feel like i'm going
through a rollercoaster and it is it is it just doesn't get any it just makes me
is really like rubbing salt on the wound
right now it's like exacerbating the injury at this point and i don't know
what to do this [ __ ] bucket stanley had never seen the office this brightly
lit was it a sign of something no he hoped it was he hoped very much that it
was the good old bucket just standing in the bucket off on another thrilling
adventure together stanley clutched the bucket tightly to
his chest and entered the door on his left
what if i don't go anywhere huh what if i don't go anywhere what if i
just chill here huh i say [ __ ] it i don't go anything
through any of those doors i just say here it's me and you hey there
hi it's me shoto how you doing today
ignore the bucket for a second and look at me all right
yeah [ __ ] the game [ __ ] the doors [ __ ] the [ __ ] the narrator okay
just look at me all right
cool go around the same page nice nice nice all right
so uh what you're doing this weekend
it's thursday tomorrow's friday and it's gonna be saturday and sunday right you
wanna you wanna do something together
you wanna go somewhere how about we go somewhere i feel like i wanna go
somewhere i wanna i'll go out
i'll be somewhere do something i wanna touch grass eat ass
and go fast
no no
i wanna i want to go somewhere i'm gonna go somewhere
i'll be here with this bucket anymore maybe i do
maybe i'm lying to myself stanley just stood there doing nothing
at all he seems to think i have nothing better to do with my time than to sit
around and describe every fascinating little detail of his ability to do
anything this is why stanley and i are on such good terms
oh my god it worked it [ __ ] worked
all right let's just chill here for a bit
i know he's gonna he's gonna eventually just say something else
he's gonna be easy to say something else and know it know it
what am i drinking i'm drinking a cup of earl grey
with a little bit of uh honey honey and earl grey tea
as any of her my throat
this is nice isn't it we get to just talk to each other and chill
just me and you not a worry in the world right
we're just chilling in the air it's like we're laying on the couch
just vibing don't have to worry about a silly
british british now right uh as in his bucket
agenda
the entire time
nope nothing at all nothing at all
okay maybe maybe i can't do anything he doesn't seem like he's saying anything
right now narrator hello
narrator
no okay
oh my god i think
hmm
there's nothing left over here is there let me think about that real quick
i go down there i go down
this was not the correct way to the meeting room but stanley had felt the
bucket calling to him telling him that the employee lounge was simply the place
to be and here it is i know exactly where i
want to go again i'm going to jump off i want to jump off the knee and go down to
the catwalk again and see if anything changes
left to go back to the meeting room
now said the bucket don't go to the meeting
room go somewhere else the cargo lift yes good said the bucket now ride the
lift all the way to the top there's something up there i need you to do
stanley did not miss that voice bucket was speaking to
him it should have alarmed him of course because buckets can't talk but stanley
chose not to think about this obvious fact he was firmly convinced that the
bucket had spoken to him and he unthinkingly did whatever the bucket
asked is it gonna be the same thing again is
he gonna make me like be like oh no buckets allowed
no stop [ __ ] up there on the wall you see there's a sign right there it says
no buckets past this point stanley how could you think it was okay give me the
same thing again unless what if the problem is that you actually don't know
what is a bucket and what i know what's a bucket and what in the bucket you
can't do this to me again
mama mia what could it mean
stan it is meeting today figurine finders to me wow give me the [ __ ]
bucket where are we going today the bucket asked stanley just smiled
anywhere they went together would be perfectly fine
[ __ ] it doesn't talk the bucket does it talk stop
oh get out of my head get out of my head get out of my head get out of my head
oh wait what's this somewhere with both red and blue a large room of boxes lots
of boxes oh boy oh boy i can't wait
dude i can't [ __ ] wait we're gonna go all the way back up to the boss room
yeah i'm gonna go here and then the code is two eight four five ariel to the
yes this is certainly the most logical explanation
let me down maybe i am losing it i'm not making up
no no i'm just i'm just i'm just
spiraling i feel like i'm spiraling my my my brain is a haze right now it's
full it's clouded it's full of bubbles
mind control facility all right what's in here huh
what's in here what's the big idea
on an enormous room packed with television screens
what horrible secret did this place hold stanley and the bucket both wandered to
themselves
stanley and the buckets and the buckets
and the buckets the monitors jumped to life and stanley
nearly dropped the bucket in shock everyone in the office was being
videotaped is there a bucket in one of these
wait what about the ones that are fired like this and who's the fired ones burst
into cradled it tears
reassuring it that everything would be fine
i cradled the bucket gently and caressed the bucket i i then firmly pressed my
lips onto the metallic surface of his of his ridges his his triple ridges and
then i grab the wooden handle of the bucket lift it up and put it on top of
my like
was the bucket under the mind control facility's influence as well had the
bucket been told to do things he didn't wish to do
what kinds of things does a bucket want to do or not want to do in the first
place yeah i don't know i don't know i really don't know man
don't know anything i don't even i can't even comprehend what you're saying at
this point he screamed into the bucket he couldn't accept it his own life in
someone else's control never he squeezed the bucket tighter his one
friend the entire world bucket at this point he could trust no one except for
the bucket
but here was the proof the heart of the opera being
eating working all of it monitored and commanded from this very place
and as the cold reality of his past began to sink in we're gonna get out
here together bucket don't worry don't worry we're gonna get out of here
we're getting out of here buddy me and you me and the bucket
stanley in the bucket waited in blackness
was it over is it over it's over [Music]
yes it's over stanley it's over defeated
their greatest and darkest enemy freed themselves from the tyrannical grip of
the evil mind control machine freedom was now mere moments away
excitedly the two of them began to discuss the kind of life they wanted to
live once they stepped through this massive me in the bucket my kid wanted
to learn to roller skate stanley wanted to sneeze in every country on earth why
both of them wanted to begin watching a movie any movie but then stop it halfway
through and begin watching it in reverse from the end
true it was a simple life they envisioned but it was one they'd lived
together with one another to lean on to trust to support
hello wait what was happening no why had the door stopped no was stanley in the
bucket not about to be no no let me out please silence though let me out
lingering oh no
the truth hit stanley square in the face this building did not want the bucket to
leave even the facility itself recognized the
incredible calming presence of the buffet needed the soothing warmth of the
bucking will go to any lengths not to part with the bucket what but
stanley can't leave this place not while he has such a precious bucket in his
arms not while this building has anything to say about it
stanley realized he would never again leave this very room but at least at
least he has the bucket to be trapped eternally in darkness isn't really so
bad stanley thought to himself as long as i have my bucket with me right i'll
be okay won't i stanley goat very soon now
he was about to find out
wha i'm fine i was about to leave oh
wait oh my god wait hello
there's a phone ringing
good morning thank you for contacting the future happiness foundation we are
confirming your shipment of 1 327 cardboard boxes to your place of
work can you verify that this is correct
excellent your order will arrive shortly thank you again for contacting the
future happiness foundation
anyways i i guess we're getting carver boxes you
[ __ ] you little [ __ ] you little [ __ ] you were the one thing that was gonna be
between me and escaping this place you know that you were the one barrier the
one obstacle that i couldn't surmount to leave this never-ending hell it's all
because of you it's literally all because of you look at your rusty ass
yeah shut the [ __ ] up
i'll need you i never needed you
a good bucket a strong bucket a humble bucket a committed bucket a bucket of
culture and distinction
stanley clutched the bucket tightly to his chest and entered the door on his
left
what do i do i don't know where to go guys guys where the [ __ ] do i go now
i don't know where to go if i go here let's just go like the same stuff that
was before and if i go here oh my god oh my god wait the cardboard wait hold on
hold on wait a room of large cardboard boxes
maybe this was not the correct way to the meeting room but stanley had felt
the bucket calling to him telling him that the employee lounge was simply the
place to be and here it was at the bucket maybe you
know maybe there's more cardboard boxes there now the bucket was wrong
stanley took the door on his left to go back to the meeting room
now said the bucket don't go to the meeting
no go somewhere else no cargo lift yes go there wait what is that cargo lift
how do i get there whoa wait a second
oh my god i'm pogging oh my god
you're getting close now stanley you've nearly gotten all of the figgler and
marines very soon you'll collect the last one and then the first number will
equal the second number and that will be it
we'll be different people by then different in the sense that we used to
have none of them and now we have them all you can't go back to when you had no
figure and marines none of us can okay
wait does that mean i can fall from here and not die
hold on is this is this a safe
fall can i fall down here like
reliably i don't know hold on let me go over here there's something in the vents
isn't there
hello
hello where the [ __ ] are we
ah
where is this it doesn't look doesn't look very
familiar very quiet
okay this is day number 295
tate number new person i don't even know i've lost track
nothing feels real anymore
the longer i study this bucket the less you lost me
anything mike you [ __ ] lost me when you said bucket the sheer
euphoria i feel every time
i pick it up no matter how many times i've done it
it's always the same feeling
and the emptiness in my chest when i set it down
it doesn't make sense
there's no explanation for it still he's australia i haven't figured
out why i see the world so differently when this bucket is in my arms
why everything feels so sorry
what do i do with this treasure treasure i can
i like it i can monetize it what monetize the bucket
it's unthinkable the amounts of money people will pay for even just an hour
with the bucket this that sounds sass it's my golden
that sounds kind of sus but i have to be careful
because as soon as this gets out there's going to be a target on my back
even now i don't know who might be trying to get
what's that who's there
[Music]
you sure this ain't a horror game yo
are we gonna pretend like that never gonna happen
narrator
hello all of his co-workers were gone oh what could it mean oh these are all the
they decided to go to the meeting room oh my god these are all the cardboard
boxes we ordered hey
what's up [ __ ] the embrace of an old friend a withered
companionship that stands the test of time stanley clutched the bucket tightly
to his this was not the correct way to the meeting room all in this together
[Music]
i'm going to go down to the bottom i want to go to the bottom not the left
don't go to the meeting room go somewhere else the cargo lift yes go
there i won't die surely i won't die if i jump from this but stanley feared that
anybody walked might lead to the separation of himself and the bucket his
dearest friend so he threw himself to his death that
they might die in one another's arms how deeply touching
all of his co-workers will go what happened to the cardboard boxes
stanley decided to go to the meeting room perhaps he had simply missed a memo
but it made stanley want to be a better man and a better co-worker in time
perhaps he would become both of those hey babe
you make me you know you you make me i want to be
a better man i won't be better for you babe
only the best version of myself that can be just for you babe
what the [ __ ] is that is this what is this what he wants
this bucket is making me lose where is somewhere both red and blue
somewhere that is both red and blue so does that mean somewhere purple
because red and blue equals
red and blue doors oh alright hold on
where's the red and blue doors area oh does that mean i have to not take the
bucket because remember when we got to the red
door in the blue door area we we didn't have the bucket with us so does that
mean i can't take the bucket with me to get
to that area when he was like
all of his co-workers were gone what could it mean
danny decided to go to the meeting room perhaps he had simply missed a memo
yeah let's try it we're not bringing the bucket this time sorry guys when stanley
came to a set of two open doors this was not the correct way to the meeting room
and stanley knew it perfectly well now how do i get to the door in the right
door
what did i do last night here it was the lounge
but eager to get back to business stanley took the first open door on his
left no sir no i didn't i'll not do that stanley was so bad at
following directions it's incredible he wasn't fired years ago
wait if i go down hold on hold on if what if i if i go to the vents
and i don't have the bucket does it change
like if i go to that room inside the vents but i don't have the bucket
wouldn't that be different hold on
stanley had now gotten himself so far off the beaten path that it seemed the
office had begun just so far off the beaten path that it seemed the office
had begun just so far off the beaten path that it seemed the office had begun
you didn't think i was actually just a recording did you what a silly and trite
explanation that would be all the back and forth between you and me all the
absurd adventures we've been through and it all turns out i'm just a tape
recording it was all justin stanley's head
i bet that's the kind of twist you think is revelatory i bet each and every time
you watch a movie where it turns out all to be in the main character's
imagination you must absolutely bolt off the couch in pure shock at the
phenomenal and intricate storytelling it must be so simple to be you
life being an unending waterfall of surprises you're assuming a lot of
things about them how much more exciting you must find the world than the rest of
us do ah
now i've become sad look what you've done to me this is all your fault
he's sad oh and he just kicked me out okay well damn that's all i get
wait someone's calling again hello hi
i'm i'm stuck here i'm done i just wanted to leave you a message to let you
know there's a few things i need you to pick up on your way home from work today
we need milk cereal dish soap spaghetti get a thing of sugar
some bread and coffee beans whichever ones you like i'll give you a call if
there's anything i forgot thanks sweetie see you tonight
was that my wife or was that like number 434 oh okay
so i had to get milk cereal dish soap a thing of
spaghetti some sugar and and my favorite coffee beans is that what she said
did i remember all the time i came to a set of two open doors this was not the
correct way to the meeting room and staff this is not the correct way to
stop by the employee lounge first whose wife is that right now i don't know i
guess it's my wife now it was okay my wife now well to get back to business
ncr the first open door on his left maybe i'm the wife
stanley was so bad by the way it's incredible
my wife
look stanley i think perhaps we've gotten off on the wrong foot here i'm
not your enemy really i'm not okay if i go over there that's the blue and red
door stuff right difficult but the fact is that the story has been about nothing
but you all this time if i do i jump off to go to the doors or do i go over there
someone you've forgotten about jump down do i jump down to go to the doors stop
trying to make every decision really
i was in the middle of something do you have zero consideration for others are
you that convinced that i want something bad to happen to you why i don't know
how to convince you of this but i really do want to help you to show you
something beautiful look let me prove it let me prove that i'm on your side give
me a chance
save at this moment stanley this is a real accomplishment this oh my god
something just for the sake of we [ __ ] did it where so many people
expect to be rewarded for the most trivial achievements
you've insisted that a job well done is its own reward do i not get a reward
i'll tell you that i'm proud of you for collecting them all but that would be
like a reward and we can't have that so instead i'll just say it's done we're
all done here and now we can go to whatever the hell you were doing before
you hunted for food wait i got scammed i didn't get a reward that's it
there's no reward oh my god now listen carefully this is important
stanley walked through the red door
perhaps you misunderstood stanley walked through the red door i still don't think
we're communicating properly stanley all right fine go ahead stanley you want to
know so badly what's out there you want to find out what okay now i can go back
to the beginning of the game ah
are you do i really get nothing out of that
oh sorry but i have to put a pause on things it's just it's those figurines
what is this those figures oh my god that scared me since you have
every last one wasn't it just the most intrinsically fulfilling moment of your
entire life didn't it fill you to the brim with inner richness
yes i know we're supposed to be telling a story but won't you please indulge me
with one more trip back to the memory zone
i would love nothing more than to revisit the figurines
just one more time oh my god this man is
oh you gotta make me lose my mind man okay fine we'll go back we'll go back if
that makes you so happy we instantly found the collectibles we
literally found them like within the hour you're acting like i found them
back in 2010.
okay ah
here's where it all began the first collectible back then we had
no idea of how many of them we'd find sure it's at six right there on the
screen but how could we know for certain we were so innocent
we'll never be like that again stanley
wait where is this
where is this i hear something creepy wait and here was a second stan marine
i'll be honest back then i had no faith in you to find any of them let alone six
but you continue to surprise me in all sorts of mundane unremarkable ways
okay let's do a little quiz huh which of these rooms was the room you found your
third mini stand can you remember
i think we found it in the bathroom i'm pretty sure that's where we found it
right hey that's exactly right it was here in
the boss's bathroom it was the third one you picked it up and then after that you
had three of them i didn't pick up the first one by accident it was so crystal
clear in your memory but i shouldn't be surprised after all science tells us
that it's impossible to forget your third time doing anything
it's impossible to forget my third time doing anything
let's see what came next oh yes we found a fig in this pink room
oh well i can't actually say i remember being in this room we were never here
before the memory zone so it must have happened
why
this was the fifth ministan and this one was really something special it was in
the warehouse i remember it so clearly in fact because this one is particularly
special to me i made a little video to commemorate the occasion enjoy you made
a video
[Music]
i i hate this game of so much what is this
2005 edits style oh my god bro
this is so dumb this is so dumb
[Music]
best boy
takes you back doesn't it i spent a lot of time making that video but it was
eight minutes i wouldn't have spent on anything else
and now where am i going
what the [ __ ] even what's that i don't know
what even was that and then right then we came to the last collectible yeah the
final figurine right here by the red and blue doors this memory is the most
distinct and clear in my mind perhaps because it was the one that happened
more recently than all the others you're you're a funny guy
you know that works all i know is that this is the moment where you picked up a
fig and i thought to myself yes that's all of them they're all collected it was
a moment unlike any other except for the other moments picking up
figurines which it was exactly like
oh wait they're both to the same area
you are in the present and then
there was no more because we've caught up to the present moment nothing left to
do would move onward into the future goodbye memory zone
um no no no i'm not done i'm not ready to
move on stop the loading screen isn't there some way we can stay here keep
enjoying these figurines let's just go backwards no we'll do the memory zone
again from the opposite direction see how that feels
i'm scared i don't want to go back i don't want to go back
what is this man doing to me
all the illusion of choice yes sir okay yes the room with the red
and blue doors i remember this i must say of all the figurines we
looked at in our initial tour of the memory zone this one he's making me do
it again clear in my mind oh my god get me out
you better not play another video don't you remember the video we watched
yes love that video
you you showed it to me like one second ago
what the [ __ ] what the [ __ ] is happening you don't
remember the pink room stanley still no memory of this one yeah this one's weird
though a solid room i don't think we got it from the pink room did we get it from
the pink room i don't remember i really don't remember
these really were a treat to hunt down you know if there had been any kind of
reward for finding all of these it really would have muted the intrinsic
joy of collecting them i'm very glad we resisted the temptation next one
is definitely a horror game i am
living hell
right now this was our second fig don't you
remember yes i remember i remember it because this is like the third time
why does anyone ever choose to leave it keep going
oh wait hold on wait let me grab it oops sorry okay i grabbed it 16 16.
wow we missed this place this is it the very first one we found in the exhibit
where i introduced you to the figurines oh i want more memories stanley i want
to keep going [ __ ] you i want out before this
i want out get me out of here
oh what is this collectible oh yeah this is back where in the beginning
yeah get me out get me out give me i gotta escape i got you out here the
terrible new content that we were originally sold on oh man i gotta leave
i gotta leave the time does we need to get out
oh yes the two doors oh god [ __ ] that a classic memory
this one
what's wrong with him and before everything else there was
your office
yeah is there anything else was there something that came before your office
there's something i feel i can remember i can remember i can remember
what do you remember yes i'm remembering something now
i remember before this whole story got started back then i was
i was different i used to make big decisions i was
passionate i was skeptical i weighed each decision with profound
thoughtfulness and then somewhere along the way i stopped making decisions
i became lazy and i came up with well came up with a character named stanley
to do my thinking for me he would make the decisions he would decide which way
to go i would cheer him on as he collected
figurines for no reason why did i invent stanley
was i lonely yes perhaps that's it perhaps i needed to imagine i had
companionship and stanley really did make for a wonderful companion even if
he was a fiction but i suppose it's grown old i
i want to think for myself again i want to go back to how it used to be
yes i can be on my own again i can do it i'll be stronger this time i'll take
care of myself i don't need stanley anymore oh but he truly was so much fun
to play with you know what
since we're in the memory zone how about one more good memory let's go back just
once and give stanley one more run of the office and then i'll retire him for
good i did enjoy telling his story so very much okay
here we go this is the story of a man named stanley
the end is never the end i think i think that's the end though wait hold on is
that actually the end or is it is like okay how about we do it one more time
and he just it's just like a loop again we do literally everything again i don't
know or that is i think that's it right
maybe one more one more
all of his co-workers were gone what could it mean
you missed some endings
not everyone is so lucky to have a bucket but stanley is a very it's a loop
guys guys it's a loop i'm pretty sure it's a loop and it's just like oh how
about we do it one more time and then they're gonna bring me again through
everything yeah
okay okay
look it's never ending this game never ends it just goes on forever okay
ah
i am i have been put through
a lot of mental torment from this game
was it fun yes it was but
did it break me yes it did it broke me somehow it broke me
i i i can never
look at a bucket the same way again dude
i can never look at a bucket the same [ __ ] way again without thinking about
the tractor i'm gonna look at a tractor and be like is this a bucket
like you know how much damage that is that's a lot of damage
that's a lot of damage my guy
ah okay i'm gonna drink some water give me a
second
i'm done i'm done that's it
we are done with the stanley parable there is no more there is no more
stanley there is no parable why it is only shoto there is only shotgun now
okay there is only shoto only shotpo only
shoto okay
only shot though oh
my goodness bro what a [ __ ] game
i i'm not okay i'm not okay i need to i feel like
here's what i'm gonna do here's what i'm gonna do to help myself i'm gonna go
take a shower i'm gonna sit in the shower
listen to uh i don't know listen to some keshie just sit in there for like 10
minutes maybe like open my mouth and like you
know let the let the shower water like spray against my tongue but i'm not
actually gonna drink the shower water i'm just gonna like let it like you know
impact my tongue because it feels kind of funny when it does that i like it and
and after that i'll get out of the shower right
i'm gonna go out actually touch some grass
right go to the gym come back be a little responsible and then i'm
gonna play video games i'm just gonna play whatever video game i want maybe i
want to go pew pew maybe i won't play league of legends maybe i want to play
final fantasy i don't know i'll play something but
i want to touch some grass because
i i gotta i don't know this is this game makes me
feel like i need to to get out of the room i don't know
it's just like it makes me feel like this existential crisis like i need to
escape now i don't want to be in inside my room at the moment i gotta like run
outside okay and just and just like breathe in the air maybe pet some dogs
maybe i'll go to the park and pet some more dogs dude i saw a husky and a shiva
the other day i had to pet both of them that was pog as hell i love those dogs i
wanna see them again the game entirely multiple times
i don't know i really don't know my name's not jim my
name is not jim anyways i'm gonna quit to the main menu
okay ah
thank you everybody for coming by today though it means a lot that
you were here to relive through that experience with me even though like it
was it was suffering you got to see me like break a little bit
to get to the epilogue you have to reboot the game entirely multiple times
oh my god really reboot the game entirely multiple times
holy [ __ ] also satsui thank you for the thousand
bits you keeping for the 300 3 000 bits and then i'm leaving for the donald as
well um
and uh priscilla priscilla thank you for the tier one thank you for the bits uh
thank you for the tier one uh chloe thank you for the gift sob andrea thank
you for the bits oats thank you for the bits too
thank you for the [ __ ]
breath some fresh air have some sweet f the bucket
f the bucket do you are you trying to sell me you want me to [ __ ] the bucket
or are you saying hey yeah [ __ ] that bucket no one cares about that bucket
because it comes off in two different ways i don't know
uh and i'll let me see who else who else
who else jess thank you for the five gifted subs and umi-san thank you for
the five uh it's your own gift subs as well and some kiwi thank you for the
zono and rinwin thank you for the doll now
and uh
really thank you for the download too and uh see thank you for the uh five
gift subs still and emil angelo thank you for the attendance you want to give
subs dale thank you so much
wow i know there's more endings
i know there's more endings but i will probably approach those endings again
when i feel like it or just because like you know i'll be like sure why not i'll
go check these out since there's a lot of them right i know there's a lot of
them but reasonably i feel like it's gonna
take me a while to like you know explore each and every single one of them they
just take me a bit but i'm going to go look for someone to
raid thank you guys for coming by today tomorrow
tomorrow we're playing fatal frame i really was thinking about playing
fiddle frame today instead but i just felt like we've had so much horror
content back to back i don't think i want to just like drown myself in too
much spooks i gotta like give myself a break and man this was a break all right
ah this was quite the [ __ ] first it broke me as a break it broke me
it did its job so um yeah i'm ready for fatal frame tomorrow
i heard a lot of good things about fatal frame a lot of you guys liked it
everyone a lot of people recommended it so let me try it out and see how it goes
i'm scared though i know it's hard i know it's really spooky
so um i'll see you tomorrow for that and uh thank you for coming by okay
if you guys haven't joined the discord already uh it's discord.json
um i usually post announcements there about
when i go live and subscribers also get like access to additional content so hey
i might post something there sometime soon so you guys can like take a sneak
peek at what's been going on also uh be sure to follow me on twitter
and subscribe on youtube i posted a new video on youtube recently so check that
out okay
all right have a good night guys i'm gonna look for somebody to raid but i'll
play a quick ad in the meantime so brb give me a second
what a [ __ ] game though oh my god what a [ __ ] game dude i would rather
like um i i don't know instead of like the
the bucket i think it's just the bucket that's getting to me something about the
[ __ ] bucket
jesus i like the the moment i started to snap
was when the game introduced the bucket like that was the turning point that was
the moment i snapped
god damn okay let's see who's live right now
oh yeah i'm gonna go hard at the gym today i really all wanted to i really
want to uh i don't know since i didn't go yesterday i'm gonna make up for it
today and uh do a little bit more it's because like my
my upper my upper shoulders were a little bit sore for some odd reason so i
didn't wanna like overdo it right and like you know hurt myself it's good to
take breast days when you can we're gonna go and read
uh
a canadian youtuber and um i think she does a lot of variety
content as well and um very cute as a fun little voice i think
you guys would like her model she's very sweet as well so share some love
okay let's see
i think this is right
take care guys have a good night i love you
[Music] sleep well okay i'll see you tomorrow
[Music]